Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Got this, though.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, with the 19… You have a vague recollection.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That… what… You all would call souls the Fey May.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The Fae were under the impression that the dream world was primary, and the plane of souls was a reflection of that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Rather than the plane of souls being primary, and the dream world a reflection of that, which…
Tim Sackton: Although this may not actually be true.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's a little muddy, but your impression is that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It may be that when this thing is talking about dreams and dreaming, it's actually talking about souls.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or that there's some kind of a conflation between those two things here.
Kate Sackton: Em.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay. More accurately, that… The child was apparently taught by someone who conflated those two things together.
David S. Kong: Was it, the Lipo of F.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Mike: Yeah, I thought that was fairly… clear from this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right.
David S. Kong: I love that shit. That's fucking awesome Okay.
Mike: What like? Clearly, there's this perception of the dreamers as
Mike: Mortals and the dreaming as some.
Mike: Conflation of mortals, and… and And,
Mike: Of mortal dreaming and mortal being.
Mike: Right? That's what I took from this, is that this talker is conflating those two things.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmhm.
Mike: Right, which I think canonically is a…
Mike: Faye is a potentially rare, is an undeterminedly common.
Mike: Faye attitude, but I know at least one page in Talk of First mentions this as something some Faye think is potentially true.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Precisely.
David S. Kong: You guys know, you guys know the Lee Poe.
David S. Kong: The Chinese poet.
David S. Kong: Yeah, you're, you'.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're all gonna wake up and realize that you're butterflies. Exactly. Horrible, terrible, disgusting butterflies with fingers that are houses.
Kate Sackton: Mmhm.
David S. Kong: That's way more awesome than I was thinking, but.
Mike: Hehehe.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm pretty…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A lot of that nuance just doesn't come through in the translation from Depot's original writing.
Mike: Yeah. I mean, this is clearly some sort of fae who's obsessed with mortals and thinks mortals are incredibly fascinating, right? And is… and is… they, the mortals, are the most beautiful thing I've ever seen. They are wanting, and I'm reading their wantings. I mean, this is like a…
Mike: A iffily, a possibly creepy bad sort of fae, but unclear.
Mike: Who has a… a…
David S. Kong: Portal finish.
Mike: Bit of a mortal fetish, yeah. I think this Fae has a bit of a mortal fetish
Mike: They share their dreams, like, but is that their souls? Is this, like, a mortal fetish, like, I like to eat mortals?
Mike: Is this Immortal Fetish, right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We begin in the fungal greenhouse, although I guess green is not exactly the right word for it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Having entered the House of 27 Rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And wandered at random through a labyrinth of constantly changing rooms, you know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Of all sorts of design, many of which seem to be for people who were living and working there, meeting rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sleeping rooms, conference rooms, kitchens… And some of which seem to be,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Chapel, and some of which seem to be…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): workspaces like this that you're in right now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All of the rooms are 30 by 30 by 30 cubes, and they have different exits, different constellations of exits.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You think you've been through a little bit more than half of them by now and.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if everyone had joined, but I'm… I am retconning the… the room numbering. None of the rooms are marked. That sort of defeats the point, and it… it leads you down the path of trying to figure it out anyways.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you've been going through this space, accompanied,
Mike: Stop by.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Menestheus, the Drancorian mathematician and mapmaker and member of Erythrimos Lemperum, a Drancorian society dedicated to policing and keeping safe the holes, the connections, the porous places between planes of existence.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): After wandering through this house, after reading the journals of listeners, who apparently were listening in through windows to the central prison room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You come at last to the fungal greenhouse, where rows and rows of tables are filled with terraria growing on a substrate of
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Human body parts, for the most part. You see hands and arms and legs in the terraria of different sizes, and a wide array of different kinds of fungus.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): in one side of the room, you met, what's her name? You met Calypses! Calypses, the gardener.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Eclipses is an ancient, ancient, dwarven wizard.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Gardner, who claims to have become the head of Ruthmer's Lemperum after Thalestria's disappearance or death, the former head of the order, the one who made the bargain with Endlessly Ending.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Calypso says that all of the other rooms have become infected, and that
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): These white fungal fibers colonize flesh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And can eventually produce yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): take over bodies completely with mouths in their chests.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, fungus in their head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she explains that she's building a fungal golem body for herself, so that she can leave safely and rebuild the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she is… single-minded in this. It's possible she's slightly cracked, also. Like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She pretty clearly has been alone in a room for a very long time, and has been growing her own partial golems.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, Tim, why don't you put the door… I don't have room-specific stuff, but if you just put the door at the end of the promontory up, that
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): These awful things, like a pair of legs with arms coming out of them that are carrying stuff around for her, or a tiny little grapefruit-sized pair of eyes and mouth, to be a lookout for her.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's, it's sort of terrible and unnerving.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She also explains that what you're in right now is the apparatus surrounding the 27th room, surrounding the prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, she doesn't know who is actually inside that locked door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She says, the listeners…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The listeners, that is, who were listening to what the prisoner seemed to be saying, the listeners claimed that there was another door inside the 27th room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Another way out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The listener said that the prisoner was a child that was being kept from growing up or dying.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: She did.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I told you that the door to the 27th room is locked with a glass key?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That can open the front door to let you back out again.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, if you want to go out the front door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You've gotta go… to the 27th room. And, grab that key.
Mike: Wait, the key is like just in the lock? Is that the impression we have?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly.
Mike: So does that mean we'd have to unlock the…
Mike: No, it's just from the outside. So anybody…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly.
Mike: can walk up and let the prisoner out if they want.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Is that the intention.
Mike: impression.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, if that's how the door works, yes.
Mike: We don't know how the door works.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Key in the lock. Yeah.
Mike: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But presumably, yeah, you could use it to open the 27th room or to open the front door.
Mike: In the retcon.
Mike: Does that mean we have no idea if we've been in a room before or not?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, I mean, look.
Mike: Sign or sigil or marking that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, you've been keeping a running list, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministheus has, enough of the trick of the place that he thinks he can move you
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): through clever movements between the rooms, take you to rooms that you have not been to before, or take you back again to rooms you've been in in the past.
Mike: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Calypses the gardener has turned back to her intent work supervising the construction of this fungal golem. And I think the group of you has stepped back just a minute to check in with each other. So if you'll start with…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): descriptions and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think the question that I'm curious about… It's like… Where?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where are you going, or what arrangement are you honoring? Like, Hulda said, Go break the agreement.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Lord Endlessly Ending said… Break the glass key entirely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or you could ignore both of those, and just try to get yourselves out, like, where… sort of where
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where are you in terms of like trying to? What? What thread are you following?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So descriptions in that.
Mike: So… Ajak is… The big, tall… Little bit.
Mike: off-looking guy with his Night Queen armor and his large sledgehammer.
Mike: strong… 6 and a half feet tall.
Mike: But, kind of… gentler than… his impression gives you like he's sort of.
Mike: Okay.
Mike: You know, always happy to help out and likes fighting monsters and so on.
Mike: where he, you know, the most prominent feature is his armor with the sigil of the Night Queen on it, right? And his most prominent mannerism is kind of a…
Mike: obsessive.
Mike: Level of prayers, especially recently where he's been.
Mike: That's a little creepy there.
Mike: Perfect.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Perfect.
Mike: Where he's where he's at right now is.
Eric Rosenbaum: Well done, good work.
Mike: Not.
Mike: Amanda, he's not.
Tim Sackton: Anyway…
Mike: That's it.
Tim Sackton: Well, ChatGPT made it. Yeah.
Mike: He's not, he's not remotely interested in helping Holga.
Mike: That guy… screwed us.
Mike: Right? Like, he was clearly not on the up and up. He… he specifically said, you're not gonna be able to get out unless I keep the door open and then close the door on this. That felt like…
Mike: pushing us down the well, to Edric.
Mike: And so…
Mike: He's not really particularly interested in whatever deal we had with Hulda. He feels like Hulda already betrayed us and said the deal's null and void.
Mike: That doesn't mean we shouldn't… fulfill it for other reasons, but…
Mike: He's sympathetic to Endlessly Ending, and kind of feels like…
Mike: We should maybe break the key, but mostly kind of wants to get out of here, and is a little creeped out by the prisoner, and definitely doesn't want to release the prisoner if that would be bad.
David S. Kong: Oh, get him in!
David S. Kong: Still dressed for a party.
David S. Kong: Now in this, you know, crazy Rubik's Cube, mycelium.
David S. Kong: Cursed Faye situation, and is…
David S. Kong: When this whole thing started, was, like, really stoked about potentially enriching himself, and kind of, oh, this is another score, this is another deal.
David S. Kong: And then… started realizing this was just, like, way bigger, and more complicated, and just more… his brain kinda hurts. You know, this whole thing, like, hurts his brain.
David S. Kong: But he's also got this part of him
David S. Kong: Like, he's got this part of him that's like…
David S. Kong: you know, the party and the riches, and then he's got a part of him that's also, like, an elf and kind of mystical, which he usually pushes down and kind of ignores. But this whole kind of adventure
David S. Kong: I think it's been making him think a lot more about his Albin side, and…
David S. Kong: Just these ancient agreements that can be made that have really far-reaching consequences for so many beings across dimensions.
David S. Kong: And in many ways, this is probably the best thing that's ever happened to him, because I think he's probably been in this toll-in, kind of small-minded, you know, zone for quite a while, and is now suddenly like, oh, fuck, you know, there's real consequences out there, and that…
David S. Kong: You know, beings that… Have a lot of influence, and for good and bad, can really…
David S. Kong: You know? Anyway, so he's having kind of an existential crisis, and is mostly now… he hasn't figured out yet where he lands on the deeper question of, like, who we're siding with, or what we're trying to do here.
David S. Kong: But I think he is, like, having a moment of deeper reflection about his own place in this, and also kind of because he's like, well, you're not gonna really die, so he's more just sort of like
David S. Kong: Like…
David S. Kong: He's having a bit of an out-of-body existential crisis, I would say, but in a good way, in a really good way.
David S. Kong: He's growing up.
Eric Rosenbaum: Tarek.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's mostly wondering… What's in it for him?
Eric Rosenbaum: When he could get more of that stuff that made him feel like he was walking on the walls.
Eric Rosenbaum: And what the thing is in his pocket that he keeps forgetting to wonder about.
Eric Rosenbaum: And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Excellent. This is the thing that you swiped from the party to be named later?
Eric Rosenbaum: Correct.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Perfect.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Kate Sackton: Aveen?
Kate Sackton: Really wants to find the light and the joy and promote, like, the well-being of the…
Kate Sackton: People who need light and she can't figure out.
Kate Sackton: What people need in this day realm of.
Kate Sackton: Not time and not day and.
Kate Sackton: Not moon, and… All the things are missing.
Kate Sackton: But she's still got her gleaming armor, she's still looking like she's raring to go on this adventure.
Kate Sackton: And she's ready to…
Kate Sackton: keep everyone's spirits up as they figure out what is right. They will figure out what is right, and it is hard because, you know, maybe helping Lord Hulda would mean accidentally, corollarily helping Hulda, who we don't want to help anymore.
Kate Sackton: But maybe not, and… Helping Lord who…
Kate Sackton: Endless Landing would also possibly end all of these mortals being sent to this prison house to probably die here or get infected with mushrooms. Maybe we can cure the mushroom thing. That would be generally good all around, right? She doesn't know, but maybe we can do some good here. As soon as we figure out what "do some good" looks like.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Tim Sackton: So, Charo is a six-foot… Something tall, lizard folk man.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Cool.
Tim Sackton: Greenish scales along the top of his head.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: And down is the back of his neck, yellowish scales on the underside of his protruding jaw, wearing a.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I,
Tim Sackton: Nothing fancy, but well-made traveling cloak.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Over sort of a simple tunic and pants, carrying very little other than a wooden shield. Carved with a bird design on the front, slung over his back at the moment in a.
Tim Sackton: polished wooden wand that he keeps stuck in his belt.
Tim Sackton: He, He has been increasingly…
Tim Sackton: nervous about this whole experience and I think is a little bit older than the rest of the party and has
Tim Sackton: Come close to dying maybe a couple more times than everybody else, and at the moment is feeling…
Tim Sackton: Like…
Tim Sackton: Cedric is, you know, protect… you know, always thinks he's protected by his god, and the Night Queen isn't gonna let him die. Aveen is just completely optimistic about everything.
Tim Sackton: Kato, Min, and Tarek are two…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: in their own…
Tim Sackton: sense of their own immortality to worry about dying, and so he now is, like, the only… feels whether this is true or not.
Tim Sackton: Like, he's the one who's worried about whether the group's gonna even make it out of this, this…
Tim Sackton: Building alive.
Tim Sackton: And this sense of having to protect everybody is increasingly growing on him.
Tim Sackton: As he looks at all of this potentially toxic mushrooms around in this place that doesn't really seem real, especially because to Charo.
Tim Sackton: you know…
Tim Sackton: There's no life here. There's no animals, there's no insects, there's no birds. Everything has been weirdly quiet, except for these.
Tim Sackton: Mushrooms that we've now encountered and so increasingly feels like almost caught in this illusion.
Tim Sackton: And not sure whether we're going to survive.
Tim Sackton: But doesn't… is not sure he really cares about either Endlessly Ending or Holder, although push come to shove would pick Endlessly Ending.
Tim Sackton: mostly concerned with escaping this realm with none of his friends dying.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministius is a… Drankorian… mathematician and mapmaker, and is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Late 20s, with a sort of a… Perpetually aggrieved and bewildered expression.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He may not still be in shock exactly about having jumped forward 700 years in time.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But, neither is he comfortable with it. He's dressed in this strange, sort of old-fashioned way, with knee breeches and stockings and soft leather low boots.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With a satchel with a couple of books in it, and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The… a belt with lots of little pouches that you associate with
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Spell components, and writing supplies, and all of that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he, he sighs deeply and wearily, and just says, this we… I… What are we… Why…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And puts a hand over his face and trails off into silence.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The… Gardener looks over at you and says, well.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Are you staying? Are you going?
David S. Kong: Wait, did Tarika…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think everyone went.
David S. Kong: Oh, sorry, I missed it. Okay.
Tim Sackton: So what are we doing, guys?
Tim Sackton: I don't see much point in staying here.
Mike: Mmhm No, how do we find this?
Mike: Bro.
Mike: No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Vinicius looks.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): out between his fingers and says, I think,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I figured out how to move it. I can get us to the rooms we haven't been to yet.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Delete.
Mike: I forget, did we… was it just a theory, or did we actually determine that we have to go to all the rooms we haven't been to in order to get to the 27th room?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think it was a theory.
Mike: Okay.
Kate Sackton: I think that… The gardener is giving… has…
Kate Sackton: Didn't the gardener… that's what we thought, right? But didn't the gardener say we just.
Tim Sackton: To the very middle.
Kate Sackton: Well, that's she told us how to get to the door out.
Mike: Yes.
Kate Sackton: Her trick was for getting to the door, but we can't open the door. To the front door.
Kate Sackton: To the front. We can't get to the front door without the key.
Mike: We can't get through the front door.
Kate Sackton: We can get through the front door.
Tim Sackton: What good does it do us to go out the front door?
Kate Sackton: Well, if we're not infected with mushrooms
Kate Sackton: The road guards won't yell at us, or won't attack us, and we'll be able to
Kate Sackton: Go anywhere we want in the stay realm until we find a portal home.
Kate Sackton: I don't know what other dangers are outside this house, but we know what dangers are inside this house, so if we're more worried about them than the unknown ones, we could just try to get out of here.
Kate Sackton: No one's really promised us a home, a portal that goes directly where we want it to go.
Kate Sackton: The only portal like that we know of is the one… to Dandelion Place.
Kate Sackton: Right, which we did.
Mike: I think we're gonna be able to easily open.
Mike: Because he'll just shut it on us.
Kate Sackton: Oh, they shed it on us.
Kate Sackton: And even if we make his dreams come true, and everything magically pops into blowing good shape on the other side of the door, and he realizes that he's the permanent owner of Dandelion House.
Kate Sackton: He probably still won't let us out, because then he'd have to pay us.
Mike: Maybe she would.
David S. Kong: What's the name of the math guy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministius?
David S. Kong: Cato turns to Mnestius, and sorry if we had none of this conversation, but it's like… it's like… does… has Mnestius… did Mnestius interact with the wizard?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With the, sorry, with the gardener or the head of the order?
David S. Kong: The head of the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Just a little bit, just…
David S. Kong: Oh, oh, okay. Yeah, I mean, Cato's like, well, what do you think of this whole bargain? Do you like your boss?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I absolutely trusted Celestia, and I believe profoundly in the work that Erythra Muslim Parham does. I mean, I gave my life to this thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Apparently, I've given a dozen lifetimes to this thing now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I trust you, I don't… I don't know about this place, but no, go ahead.
David S. Kong: Yeah. Where do you think she is? Like, what do you what do you think? And what do you think about this agreement? What do you think the agreement was between.
David S. Kong: Sorry, what's the name again? Illust.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Celestia.
David S. Kong: Philestria. What do you think about that was the agreement between, or why do you think Philestria is having endlessly ending send mortals down the road? What do you think is going on here?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We know from Calypses that And he…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Glances over to see if she's looking, and then puts "no" in scare quotes. We…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I know from calypsies that… The prisoner at the center…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's like they have to be constantly moving. It's like… it's like taking a prisoner and moving them from one prison to another to another to another, so they… they can't ever stay in one long enough to figure out how to break out of it, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We know from her… That the thing that keeps it moving is going back and forth between these rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Velestria must have made some… why it has to be mortals and not fae, I don't know, but… Velestria must have made some…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Celestia made sure that this prison was safe when she left it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Now, I don't know, but I know she wouldn't stop. She wouldn't stop here. There was, I mean, dozens of places that needed to be sealed or kept.
David S. Kong: Oh my gosh, do you think that then this prisoner is somebody who's trying to create disorder?
David S. Kong: And actually, you know, create breakages between worlds, whoever's in here.
David S. Kong: Do you have any idea who's in here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't. It…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Look, I'm still… Relatively.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Early in my process here, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Calypses is like my boss's boss's boss's boss's boss's boss.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
David S. Kong: Oh, so let's ask her.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She already said she doesn't know who is inside it.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But, Ministeus will say one more thing, which is,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But the impression I always had.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Is that…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That whatever is locked up in there, it's not, it's something that's not right. It's like, it's…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Another reason that I became a member of the Order is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I was raised on a steady diet of fairy tales.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Of the unlife.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's waiting to undo life.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): of… Bargains struck and disasters averted, and I wanted to be a part of that And I didn't go…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Into politics, and I didn't go…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Into theory, I wanted to go somewhere where…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I would make a difference against whatever.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): those things are that are incomprehensible. The thing about holes in the universe is.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The things on the other side don't make sense.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They don't make sense.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
David S. Kong: Cato's, like, so blown away hearing somebody talk about having, like, a purpose. It's like, wow.
David S. Kong: Holy shit.
David S. Kong: That's awesome, dude.
David S. Kong: I respect that.
David S. Kong: Where's the mushroom grower?
David S. Kong: Lady?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She's just off down the row a little bit, working on her go.
David S. Kong: And she is also in the order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes. She believes she is the head of the Order, and that Thalestra is dead.
David S. Kong: Oh, shit.
David S. Kong: Why do you think Sylvester is dead.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think just that it's been hundreds of years.
David S. Kong: Huh.
David S. Kong: And what's her last? What did we learn from talking to her?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She thinks there's an infection running rampant through this space. You learned how the space works as a prison to keep moving in time and space.
David S. Kong: But she doesn't know who's being imprisoned either.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, she's obsessed with keeping the Order alive. So she's making this golem body for herself to get out and restart it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But…
David S. Kong: Oh, cool.
Mike: 08:00 AM.
Mike: Isn't it kind of… Thank you.
Mike: If nobody moved, if everybody was still, if no new people ever came in here, wouldn't the prisoner break out?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah. Presumably, yes.
Mike: So don't we think that… breaking… The treaty between…
Mike: Sorry, breaking the… freeing, endlessly ending from the curse? Won't that free the prisoner?
Kate Sackton: Possibly.
David S. Kong: Yes, yes, actually. Totally.
Kate Sackton: Consequence that we might have to, we might.
Mike: Are you sure.
Kate Sackton: Helping Hulda, we might end up unleashing the prisoner into the world.
Mike: Helping Hulda, won't that unleash the prisoner.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Kate Sackton: Yes. Helping end the ending would help.
Mike: It's the same thing. I do see how they can hold out the same gold, don.
David S. Kong: Yes, they both do.
Mike: Agreement?
David S. Kong: Yes.
Kate Sackton: Right.
Mike: They both want this agreement broken.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Mike: Right?
David S. Kong: Yes.
Mike: And, and… We think it's pretty clear, from everything we've learned, that breaking that will release the prisoner, right?
Kate Sackton: Right, the prisoner who's generally described as the child, the dreamer. I'm.
Mike: Yet.
Kate Sackton: Things about trees!
Mike: But also.
Kate Sackton: Neat.
Mike: Maybe Eats Mortal Souls?
Kate Sackton: Doesn't Doesn't say that in the notebooks.
Kate Sackton: Well.
Mike: Well, is that, is that true?
Kate Sackton: Interested in mortal souls and eats them is different?
Kate Sackton: I'm interested in the moon!
Mike: Some are hungry, like me.
Kate Sackton: You.
Kate Sackton: It's been in prison.
Kate Sackton: It's hungry for something.
Mike: Yeah, what else did it say? Something that was even creepier.
Mike: There was something creepy in here.
Eric Rosenbaum: But.
Mike: But, you know, I didn't get the impression that the prisoner was, like, super safe.
Kate Sackton: I'm not saying the prisoner's safe Just…
Eric Rosenbaum: Schwartz, if you pin those comments, Kong will be able to see them since he joined after they appeared in the.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You will lose.
David S. Kong: Great, thank you.
Mike: Like, I mean… Yeah, maybe. I'm just, I'm just saying, are we really, like,
Mike: Are we really sure we wanna, you know… Help… help this guy escape?
Kate Sackton: So… Have we asked?
Kate Sackton: Eclipse.
Kate Sackton: The eclipso eclipses.
Kate Sackton: what she plans like does she have any
Kate Sackton: Capacity for navigating between the Fey Realm and Drencor.
Kate Sackton: Like, if she gets out.
Mike: Yeah, how.
Kate Sackton: So in a mushroom body, what good does that do her either?
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Kate Sackton: rebuilding the order if she's also trapped in the F
Kate Sackton: Push her. Let's ask her that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): She'll, without even turning around to look at you, she'll just wave it off.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a dozen exits from the Feywild.
Kate Sackton: Well, that's kind of what I.
Mike: Yeah, so do you know how to get to any of them?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, the closest is… Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think the closest from here is probably sunset.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's a bit of a walk, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My little mushroom body will get me there safe.
Mike: Okay.
Mike: Could you tell us how to get there, just in case we get out and separated?
Mike: Like, are there instructions, directions?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ask him, she says, pointing back to Menestheus.
Mike: Do you know how to get out of here?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I, I'm, I'm, I'm sort of.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not to make too much of myself, but I'm sort of a walking encyclopedia of the connections between planes. I'm… yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she's… Technically right that that is the closest exit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But, you know, assuming nothing new has opened up in the last 700 years, but… Oh, fuck, it's been 700 years.
Kate Sackton: Think of the updates you can make to your maps.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He stares off into space, shaking his head.
Kate Sackton: Scholastic discovery awaits!
Mike: Think of the updates you'll have to make to your maps.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yes.
Mike: Tedious.
Mike: Never mind.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Mike: So, right, but we can't get out.
Mike: Without the key, so what are we waiting for? Let's go get the key.
Tim Sackton: Yes, I agree.
Tim Sackton: Onward.
Tim Sackton: Lead us, Menesthius.
Tim Sackton: Cool.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry. The gardener waves at you without turning around. Good luck!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'll see you or I won't
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): "Sure I won't," she says under her breath.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Umm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then this leads you on stepping out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A different door than you came in, and you find yourself in, sort of a parlor and game room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's like a plush sort of a club room with big leather club chairs and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What to your eyes are, like, antique board games. Even the playing cards are a slightly different size and proportion than what you're used to.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a billiards table in one corner with a similar setup, though the balls are completely different.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's — it's a sort of a — it's a sort of a rec room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, nicely appointed, but… Nothing of notice or note.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And minister this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): waves you on, across the hall to the… the far side. This… One is new.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you step through and find yourselves in a lecture hall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are standing at the level of a long blackboard, and rows of chairs rise up to exit on the far wall on the other sides.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The things that are of note here are… On the… blackboard? Is… Diagram of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, certainly what looks like a dandelion life cycle, where at the top there's a single little puff spore, and then it shows it in soil, and then it shows it rooting, and then it shows it, you know, in the sort of circular diagram, right? Shows it,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Blooming shows the bloom becoming spores, then the single spore on the wind.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): so it's been drawn on sort of hastily onto the board.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The other strange thing about this room is the back wall.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There is a gigantic black painting, that if you want to make anything of, it's going to need more inspection, but it looks like a beautifully framed
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): what, it's got to be at least, like, 8 feet tall by 14 feet wide. I mean, one of these immense, immense canvases, oil painting that's just blackness.
Mike: Like, the whole painting's just black.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Kate Sackton: Is it?
Mike: Gradients of color? Is it like a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're welcome to investigate.
Mike: Yeah, I'll go closer, take a.
Kate Sackton: Does it look different to your eyes than it looks to mine?
Eric Rosenbaum: Wow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Umm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You see, as you get closer, there are different shades of blackness in it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, mike, you think you can discern that there's a field of stars?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With these tiny little dots of a slightly less black blackness.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And… A VIN… You see that there is a section in the center of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where there are no stars, almost as if there's a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A rip, in this field of stars, like it's torn.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This section about a foot wide, And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Come on.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the, in.
Kate Sackton: Canvas looks damaged, or like, I think I see a torn, sort of.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, you think, you know, in the painting itself, within the black on black, there's a deeper blackness, a sort of a hole where there's none of the dark stars.
Eric Rosenbaum: an image of a tear.
Eric Rosenbaum: Meanwhile, Tariq is wondering… Oh, games. Games of chance. Perhaps,
Eric Rosenbaum: Coinage or other things of value are exchanged. He's looking around for a lockbox, cash register, safe.
Mike: Didn't we already leave that room.
Kate Sackton: We left the parlor.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oops, sorry.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We did, but actually… I'm happy to do that real quick. Roll investigation.
Eric Rosenbaum: 16.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes. With that, you don't find any Money or value?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But you find a book called The Shape of Discovery.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The basic argument, it's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it's hard to tell if this is a serious philosophical treatise, or if this is a sort of a parody.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But… It's a sort of a small…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): sort of, book, and relatively brief, and flipping through it,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The argument that it makes, or the claim that it makes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Maybe as parody, maybe seriously, is that,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): curiosity is the same thing as greed, and that in the same way, this… the greed, which is the motive power of games of chance.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Curiosity works the same way to shape possibility in the world.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that curiosity, like greed, is irrational and unpredictable, and sometimes,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): takes people over with a drive to explore. But centrally, crucially, the curiosity of a person is one of the few wholly unpredictable things in a world.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Just like a game of chance.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
David S. Kong: Cato is very secure.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We'll say you're still flipping through that as you're standing in the lecture hall. Go ahead, Kong.
David S. Kong: Cato is very curious about this dandelion painting. Is this the first dandelion that we've seen in this building?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think so.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yes.
David S. Kong: Just given… given…
Kate Sackton: Everything.
David S. Kong: And so, so Schwarz, yeah, Cato goes up to just investigate anything pertaining… I mean, you said it was hastily drawn
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, give me an investigation check.
David S. Kong: Can somebody roll D20 for me? Can somebody roll D.
Tim Sackton: There was a vase of fresh dandelions in the…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Tim Sackton: bungle room that we left.
Kate Sackton: That's.
David S. Kong: Okay, good.
David S. Kong: Anybody roll? Roll D20?
Tim Sackton: Oh yeah, I got you.
David S. Kong: Thank you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: A seven.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With the seven…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You see that the chalkboard has previous things that have been erased, but you can't tell what they are.
David S. Kong: Cato's like, wave somebody over. Hey, someone else, look at this. I think there's something else going on with this board.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Other people.
David S. Kong: Three people make an investigation check.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: Believe.
Mike: And I've been in investigation.
Eric Rosenbaum: Am I still in the other room?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: No, we all have to travel between rooms together.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, okay. So I will investigate.
Tim Sackton: I'll, I'll guidance you as you walk over, I'll just, like, hold my hand up and give you a little
Tim Sackton: blessing of inspiration from the lizardfolk ancestors.
Eric Rosenbaum: How much is that? What does that give.
Tim Sackton: 1D4 to any investigation checks you make for the next minute.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay, so I rolled a eight plus four is twelve, and then I'll take my
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, they changed this menu. D4.
Eric Rosenbaum: Which is another 3, so 15 total.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ahhh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, with a 15…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It looks to you like this was,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): lecture on, wind-dispersed flowering plants.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can see a milkweed pod and a milkweed life cycle too.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, or what, maple wings,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's… whoever was here was sort of surveying wind-dispersed flowering plants.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
David S. Kong: Like, like, like teaching it, or like, is this like a lecture hall, or is this like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep. Exactly.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
David S. Kong: So, okay, is this like infection route? Is this like how do we get the… Is this how we disperse the…
Mike: Yes.
David S. Kong: Oh, is this like a master plan to infect all multiverses with this infection, whatever it is? What do we know about this infection again? What do we know about the disease thing?
Mike: Not a lot.
Tim Sackton: Turns you into things with mouths in your chest that attack the road guards.
Tim Sackton: Kill you.
David S. Kong: We know.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, let.
David S. Kong: Do we know the relationship between this disease and Endlessly Ending? And what's the name of that wizard again?
Kate Sackton: Balestria?
David S. Kong: Illustria?
David S. Kong: Like, are they supporters? Do they want to stop it?
David S. Kong: Like, well, what's the relationship between the wizard and this disease? Because this is clearly being, like, actively researched and taught inside this place, right?
Mike: Oh.
Mike: No, we have no idea.
Tim Sackton: Maybe I'll win.
David S. Kong: Not necessarily.
Mike: Yeah, well, do we even know?
Kate Sackton: I just noticed it was happening and left.
Mike: Is this this building is
Mike: Do we even know who used to be here? Like, it has the vibe of an abandoned…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Mike: place but it's kind of weird like each of the do all the rooms feel like are they connected in
Mike: decor, and… Like, it's a cohesive place, right? It's not like each room is some…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, that's correct.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep. It was a sort of a…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: He'.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A base or a hideout for Erythrimos Lemperum.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Workspace.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, I mean, presumably… Before they used it as a prison, you could actually walk from room to room.
Mike: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, you know, the other thing that the gardener told you about the disease is it changes you so that like your skin gets really pale and sort of doughy and.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You can't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it a little stronger and rounder.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Mike: Wait, that's.
Kate Sackton: No, hold on, though.
Mike: Oh, no, the serpent.
Eric Rosenbaum: -Oh.
David S. Kong: Wait, what?
Mike: Hulda's servant is infected with the disease. Hulda's servant, the round guy, is.
David S. Kong: Oh.
Mike: Dude.
Mike: Oh, maybe Holden did betray us, maybe Holden's servant bet.
Eric Rosenbaum: I wonder about the fire thing, too.
David S. Kong: What fire thing?
Mike: He didn't like fire at.
Tim Sackton: He was scared of fire.
Eric Rosenbaum: Maybe it'.
Tim Sackton: They should probably burn some things down if…
Eric Rosenbaum: It's kind of like rab.
Mike: I mean.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the gardener said they were susceptible to fire.
Mike: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, okay. We already knew that. Nice.
Mike: So Hulda's Servant Dude was definitely a fun goal.
Mike: Alden, that's his name.
Mike: Probably not really a Samarin.
Mike: Kagaverse is lying to us.
Eric Rosenbaum: Round, pale, quiet, and stronger than he looks. Hmm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Eric Rosenbaum: Are you going to sprout into a puff of spores? Oh man.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Don't do any more searching or investigating in here.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, I want to look at the painting, yes. I will just reach out and kind of, like, drag my fingers across it.
Tim Sackton: Farah will go stand right next to… just, like, subtly, as Tark does this, I'm just, like, keeping a hand on his shoulder, ready to drag him back into this world before he gets eaten by some…
Kate Sackton: Black painting.
Tim Sackton: Strange extraplanar terror.
Eric Rosenbaum: Tarek is patient with this kind of… Overcaution.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Eric, as you move your fingers over the center of the painting, where that black-on-black sort of tear in the fabric of the stars is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can… you cannot see a difference, but you can feel with your fingers a difference in texture of something in the middle.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And, It's a little tough to make it out, but it… has… Something like,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know. What do you think you feel there?
Eric Rosenbaum: Very fine fur.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, so it's like a soft, furry, like a very thin coating of fur or…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We're like a very…
Eric Rosenbaum: The finest velvet.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, or maybe like the little fine hairs of a mold covering a body in the shape of a.
Eric Rosenbaum: No, no, not that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Uhhh… In the shape of a sprouting seed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like a seed that's opened in two halves, and something is growing out from inside of it.
Eric Rosenbaum: I should probably wash my hands, but I'm not going to.
Kate Sackton: I mean, we haven't found a sink with running water yet, have we?
David S. Kong: Hand washing is overrated.
Mike: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's true. Did anything come off on me?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Nope.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it's just the texture of it. Maybe it's invisible, or maybe…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Your eyes aren't able to perceive what's going on there.
Eric Rosenbaum: Sorry, a seed.
Eric Rosenbaum: Splitting open.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm gonna see his ears perk up at that A seed splitting open?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Through a crack in the universe? That's… that's… yeah. That's… that's…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, that's terrible. Oh my god, that's terrible.
Eric Rosenbaum: What do you mean?
Eric Rosenbaum: It's just a painting.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is the sort of thing that we were set up to prevent.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Have you ever been… have you ever been, like, to really nice estates? I don't… I don't even know if you still have nice places when you all live.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not like drank corn, sure.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But like a perfectly even lawn, And then…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When someone stops taking care of it and a single dandelion seed falls in it and sprouts.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's like… it's like that.
Mike: But…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But in between worlds.
Mike: I mean, things have been okay without you for hundreds of years. You might be overthinking this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Have they though? Have they been okay?
Mike: that Recently, sure, yeah.
Kate Sackton: Have we been without him? I mean…
Kate Sackton: Celestria might be out there protecting us.
David S. Kong: Well, I mean, the prisoner is also like imprisoned, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
David S. Kong: Like, if the prisoner goes out.
David S. Kong: Maybe things change in bad ways?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Right.
Eric Rosenbaum: Why is this painting all black? Is it designed for someone who's blind?
Eric Rosenbaum: Or for someone who sees differently than we do?
Mike: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Some parts of the universe are described As being blacker than black?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Which I always thought was just poetic.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Maybe it's referring to a place, I don't.
Eric Rosenbaum: What parts?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right, onwards then.
Mike: Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmhm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room that you come into.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): is… a workshop is a clock-making workshop. A clock works.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And there are… workstations…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): on long benches and tables with intricate gears and tiny tools. There's a couple of different grandfather clocks in different stages of assembly, as well as a few different small, like, desk-sized versions of the same.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sort of grandfather clock.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's what it is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Clockworks Workshop.
Eric Rosenbaum: I looked closely at the clock faces, because wasn't… There was a… odd numeric scheme.
Eric Rosenbaum: Which we then learned about.
Eric Rosenbaum: at the party.
Eric Rosenbaum: I don't remember the scheme.
David S. Kong: What? What's that?
David S. Kong: So clearly, this is the clock, this is where they made the clock that is in, you know, this is the clock.
Eric Rosenbaum: Why? Why should there be so many of them?
David S. Kong: Prompt text.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, or maybe it's useful… I mean, it would be useful to know
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it'd be useful to know what's going on in the center like if you could take these clocks anywhere. Ministia says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Then you could be anywhere in the universe and know if the prisoner was still trapped, if the clock kept moving.
Mike: Wait, what?
Mike: What does the clock and the prisoner have to do with each other?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The clock shows…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): the time and the location of the prison, the year and its location. So there's two six-digit numbers for latitude and longitude, and then there's one four-digit number for year.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the faces that are immediately around you all just read 0 and everything, they're…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At least the things nearby are not working.
Mike: Oh.
Mike: I see.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What do you do?
Kate Sackton: There's no papers or books or… Anything in here? Just…
Kate Sackton: Actual person who was working here didn't need any instructions, notes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's diagrams that are sort of nonsensical, but yep, they're definitely diagrams. It's a combination of mechanics and magic.
Eric Rosenbaum: It seems like…
Eric Rosenbaum: It might be useful to have a working one of these, and that there are small ones. So are any of the desk-sized ones looking like they're…
Eric Rosenbaum: in the most fully functional state, or… sort of, like, been closed up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So you look and look, and eventually you do find one, which, it doesn't have, like, the top case on it, so, like, its guts are all sort of hanging out, it doesn't look finished.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But it shows specific numbers, and it's probably 5 or 10 pounds, small enough to be carried around.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, I'll carry it around.
Eric Rosenbaum: But maybe I'll, find some way to wrap it up so that it's…
Eric Rosenbaum: It's not gonna get banged around and then Crucial Gear pop out or something.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Excellent.
Eric Rosenbaum: Pick it up and Somebody cloak.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room is another of the massive mechanical rooms, and as you step into it, you do notice that the numbers on the clock face change.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): One of the three sets of numbers changes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
Eric Rosenbaum: Desktops, I'm just, what is this called? Desktop sized.
Eric Rosenbaum: Space-time grandfather clock.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Exactly.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's another one of these massive mechanical rooms where almost the entire space is filled with
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You know, just huge and sort of incomprehensible piping and tubing and gears. There's a hum to it. And there's another one of these listening stations.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With a notebook.
David S. Kong: What's in the notebook?
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So in the notebook, are another series of entries transcribed Presumably from the prisoner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I'm gonna… I'm going to paste these into chat one by one.
Eric Rosenbaum: Listen.
Mike: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Does this one have a…
Tim Sackton: The other ones were the child and the dreamer, does this one have a name?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It does. Its name is Thirst.
David S. Kong: Sorry, what's name is Thirst?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The name… so, Kung, I'm putting in chat the… The posts. Oh.
David S. Kong: Okay, great.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Transcriptions.
David S. Kong: Oh, wow.
David S. Kong: Thank you.
Mike: Okay, so like this guy's clearly.
Mike: making the fungus.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Mike: They're helping me find. So, I mean, okay, so clearly, I mean, I don't know, maybe I'm.
Mike: Thinking this is too obvious.
Mike: But…
Mike: This… and I don't know if Edric would really pick up on this, but to me, this really reads like, I'm… I'm making a child, I'm putting my children in the empty heads where souls used to go, this is the fungus guy.
Mike: Right, this is clearly the source of the focus.
Mike: Right? They're helping me find the man who is freeing me? That's… hold on, hold on.
Mike: Right? The prisoner manipulated events.
Mike: to get… The fungus dude out in the world to go find.
Mike: Some poor sectors like us, to…
Tim Sackton: you know, more…
Mike: Do I call that?
Mike: Bye.
Mike: How do we know that that elf was real?
Tim Sackton: We don't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You saw the deed. The deed looked legit.
Mike: Wasn't it, there.
Tim Sackton: Except there was recent.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It works.
Tim Sackton: Wasn't 400 years old.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It was written in a contemporary idiom despite being 400 years old.
Mike: That was fake.
Eric Rosenbaum: Thank you.
Tim Sackton: Despite appearing 400 years old.
Mike: The elf was fake. That's all fake. The prisoner was imprisoned and now he's trying to get out. He's manipulating us and we have to run away from him and he's scary and
Mike: And he wants to fill the world with seeds and spores that'll eat human souls. He wants to keep the souls from going to their gods. Actually, Edric's getting really bit- okay. Whether this is right or not, Edric's getting really worked up, though. He thinks that this guy is,
Mike: that his, like, goal is to do something to souls. He interprets that line, like, where did it… there was something I saw in here. I'm hiding the path for the souls to leave and go to the next place.
Mike: Right?
Mike: Dietrich interprets that as, I… as this is some evil creature that is keeping souls from crossing over the land to the dead and rejoining their gods.
Kate Sackton: Nope.
Kate Sackton: Nefarious.
Mike: It's the worst thing you can possibly do in the entire universe.
Mike: Dietrich gets very worked up. Like, he's passionately claiming how bad this guy is. We cannot free this guy.
Mike: He's horrible and awful. He has to stay trapped.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
David S. Kong: But we still meet him, right?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I don't know.
Kate Sackton: No, we don't need the…
Kate Sackton: I mean, Mnestis would like to keep him imprisoned, too, as part of Mnestis's life work.
Kate Sackton: We can just… Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Minnesota says, I… I trust the less chip, if…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This is who the prisoner is. They need to stay in prison. There's no question about that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't… I don't know, with all due respect, my friend.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This doesn't sound any different than a…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): an animal that eats? Animals get hungry and eat? I'm sure… I don't know.
Mike: I kill animals.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): True.
Mike: Eat souls. I call them monsters.
Mike: That's what this is for! He branches his hammer.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, that's the same thing that rabbits say about foxes.
Eric Rosenbaum: E.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm just saying, I'm just, I'm just saying maybe we should.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well, he says, looking back at the notebook, I was gonna say we should keep an open mind, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What we need, what we really need, is the order back again. If the order was here, they could take care of this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We can't figure this out on our own.
Mike: Wait, what is there to take care of? Isn't it all just working?
Tim Sackton: There was only two mortals left at the party.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Kate Sackton: Do you want to be in charge of recruiting people to come here and die so that this thing can stay trapped?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You are alternately here, Mia. We could just wander forever through this place.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, my God.
Kate Sackton: I guess for the rest of our very expanded lifespans, 'cause you're still here.
Kate Sackton: The dwarf is…
Tim Sackton: I've only found three bodies, is that correct?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Say that.
Tim Sackton: We've only found three bodies.
Tim Sackton: The three bodies.
Tim Sackton: In the sanctuary?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): in the mortuary.
David S. Kong: Sorry, I.
Tim Sackton: Why we're.
David S. Kong: Okay.
Tim Sackton: If people are just wandering endlessly… Why have we…
Tim Sackton: Both not encountered anybody and not found dead bodies.
Tim Sackton: Like, the bodies that were brought…
Tim Sackton: People in the mortuary could not have been mortals sent here by the bargain. Who would have brought them to the mortuary?
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: Well, if.
Eric Rosenbaum: Interesting.
Kate Sackton: If things started going wrong while the order was still here, and Felestria felt like she had to have a plan for restocking the
Kate Sackton: Mechanism.
Kate Sackton: Of the infected house.
Kate Sackton: Because she couldn't control the infection.
Kate Sackton: So she had mortals sent here by a fae.
Tim Sackton: But shouldn't we find dead bodies then?
Kate Sackton: Well, don't they turn into something once they die?
Eric Rosenbaum: Maybe they get consumed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Have you heard the whispering before?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Chair Member.
David S. Kong: Oh yeah, I did.
Tim Sackton: Cato.
David S. Kong: Inside the wall, when I did something, what did I do? I, like, I like…
David S. Kong: Oh boy. What the hell was I doing?
Kate Sackton: Did we all hear the whispering in the creepy portal in the chapel? Is that where we heard it.
Tim Sackton: It's when you picked up the pen.
Mike: Yes.
Mike: You picked up the pen in the notebook.
Kate Sackton: When you were, when you were writing to, yeah, if you.
Mike: You wrote it.
Kate Sackton: If you took the transcriber role, then you started hearing, you started being a listener.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dude.
David S. Kong: Yeah, I see it. I see it.
David S. Kong: Wait, but hold on, hold on, just so I remember again. What happened? What was I doing when I heard the voice?
Kate Sackton: You were taking a shift as a transcriber, basically.
Tim Sackton: Holding the pen at a journal. Yeah.
David S. Kong: But what was going on with the transcribing? What was being transcribed.
Mike: the prisoner.
Kate Sackton: You were, like, looking at the black space that was the, like, window to nothing.
David S. Kong: Yeah. Okay.
Kate Sackton: and a notebook.
Kate Sackton: Oh, because.
David S. Kong: Because the prisoner was communicating and people were writing down what he was thinking or saying.
Kate Sackton: But.
Mike: That's what we assume.
David S. Kong: So I was transcribing messages from the prisoner.
Kate Sackton: Yeah.
Mike: We think so.
Kate Sackton: But it was, like, your first message, so it was kind of weak and…
Mike: No.
Kate Sackton: Not quite as in-depth as.
Mike: Hi.
Kate Sackton: I keep the dreaming soul and its body is empty of dreaming. I'm filling it with seeds and spores.
David S. Kong: So you see Kato suddenly, he's just looking around.
David S. Kong: Anybody hear that?
Kate Sackton: No.
David S. Kong: Anybody hear that whispering?
Mike: There you go.
Kate Sackton: Let me…
Mike: And he only replies if needed once.
Kate Sackton: Do you hear it when you look in a particular direction or do a certain thing or just while we're all?
David S. Kong: Well, just that voice talking about us.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
David S. Kong: Leaving through the door in his room. You guys know? You guys hearing the thing?
David S. Kong: Nobody's hearing any voices?
Kate Sackton: Nope.
David S. Kong: Nobody else, that they're reading my thoughts, that we can't leave, we're walled in.
David S. Kong: They're full of dreams and they can't eat anymore
David S. Kong: And that they're helping.
David S. Kong: Hey Schwartz, voice in my head. I do a…
David S. Kong: Can I communicate with the voice in my head?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, you're hearing it as a whisper. You're hearing it not coming from inside, but coming from the window.
David S. Kong: Oh… which window?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The window next to the listening station. The window at the listening station.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, in the back wall of this room, there's a sort of a cutout.
David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 3 window size that looks onto a Iron… rune covered.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Whoa.
David S. Kong: Okay, so I think the prisoner is talking to me in my head.
David S. Kong: Anybody else want to try picking up the pen?
David S. Kong: I'll start.
Mike: Muttering a prayer to the Night Queen. Don't don't let it eat.
David S. Kong: Yeah, I mean, Schwartz, am I receiving the voice as like threatening in any way or kind of like, or is it like, what's the, what's the tone of the voice?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's helpful.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It wants to help.
David S. Kong: Okay. I mean, I do, I mean, Kara's got some, some, Some abilities to discern.
David S. Kong: To certain things. Hold on.
David S. Kong: Kato…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, it's speaking with a certain kind of confidence. Like, it's very… it is 100% sure of the things it is saying.
David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
David S. Kong: I mean, it really wants to help. It says there's a hole in the wall.
David S. Kong: I mean, Cato kind of whispers back, like, you're helping us do what?
David S. Kong: I don't know
David S. Kong: Is there any communication? Is it, like, bidirectional, or is it just the… can you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): by this time.
David S. Kong: Never play, okay.
David S. Kong: Well, it says that, they're always hungry, but they're full of dreams, so they can't eat anymore.
David S. Kong: And instead of eating us, We're helping it.
David S. Kong: And that it can read our dreams. Have we been dreaming?
David S. Kong: Have we slept?
Eric Rosenbaum: Good stuff.
Tim Sackton: Sleep.
Tim Sackton: Yep.
David S. Kong: Did we dream anything?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Nope.
David S. Kong: Hmmm.
David S. Kong: Okay.
David S. Kong: Well, it sounds really helpful. I mean…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In some of the previous messages, it seems to conflate dreaming and souls.
David S. Kong: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There could be some ambiguity there.
David S. Kong: Right.
Mike: If it's full of dreams, doesn't that mean it's full of souls Is he…
David S. Kong: A lot, yeah.
Mike: Yeah, so this is bad.
Mike: But it sounds so nice.
David S. Kong: Yes.
Mike: Cato will, Edric will tell Cato-Man three different stories from common myth about nice sounding things that turn out evil.
David S. Kong: Yeah, those are human stories. You're, you're, I mean, it's, this is, this is, I mean.
Mike: I don't.
Tim Sackton: Usually Fae stories, actually.
David S. Kong: Is the prisoner okay? We don't know that.
Mike: Okay, we think it is.
David S. Kong: Well, look, it says that we're leaving through the door in its room.
David S. Kong: Like, if we want to get… I mean, let's get practical here Okay.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, we're trying to find it, so…
David S. Kong: Find what?
Mike: President.
Tim Sackton: That's key.
Mike: Don't we think we can just take the key out of the door and then go back to the main room and run away?
David S. Kong: Which bedroom?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door IN its room? You mean the door TO its room.
Mike: No, there's a hole.
David S. Kong: The prisoner says, I'm talking to the prisoner, the prisoner's whispering in my head. The prisoner says that there's a door in its room. So there's both a door to its room and a door in its room.
David S. Kong: That's what I think is going on here. What do you think I think so.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that's a terrifying possibility.
Kate Sackton: gave that.
Kate Sackton: in this recent… in this set of transcriptions, where it's called the thirst. I see the door out, and it moves and moves and moves.
Mike: Do you think we have to, like, go into its room and close the door?
Mike: That sounds bad.
Kate Sackton: I mean, it sees the door out.
Kate Sackton: But the mechanism of the house keeps the door moving.
Mike: Yeah, but it can send its children through.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Kate Sackton: It's trying to destroy the integrity of the house.
Mike: No, through the hole.
Mike: The hall is big enough for my children to climb out.
Kate Sackton: Right, so it's sending its children out to destroy the prison, but it's not going out through the hole 'cause it's too big.
Mike: Holes often get bigger.
Mike: I've rarely experienced a hole in a wall that doesn't, over time, grow.
Eric Rosenbaum: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You could be one of.
Eric Rosenbaum: Awesome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let's minister this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Thank you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Fungal spores, children?
Mike: Yeah, it's children are fungal spores, and it eats souls, and we have to kill it. Let's keep going.
Kate Sackton: It fills the world with seeds and spores and roots and tendrils and.
Mike: Yes, like the dandelions, which are terrible and bad. We need to kill it, and then we need to go back to Dandelion House and burn it to.
Kate Sackton: Exactly why are we gonna be able to kill the thing that the…
Kate Sackton: Hocus-y, pocus-y cult couldn't kill and had to imprison.
Mike: Well, we might die trying.
Kate Sackton: They were kind of powerful Drangorians.
Eric Rosenbaum: But maybe they had some other motive.
David S. Kong: I don't have.
Eric Rosenbaum: around.
David S. Kong: Yeah, I mean, no.
Eric Rosenbaum: Instead of destroying it.
Mike: I mean, we could just go burn debt. We need to burn more things to the ground, that's all I'm saying.
Eric Rosenbaum: We need to.
David S. Kong: I heard you're.
Eric Rosenbaum: Cthulhu P.
Tim Sackton: Where's dad when you need him?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Every adventure, it just ends in explosion. Huge explosion.
Tim Sackton: I, in my head, I've retconned the ending of that campaign where Dev just burned the Caribbean islands to the ground and we all died in a conflagration.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that's perfect, because it was actually ineffective at eradicating the thing, but you're right.
Tim Sackton: Exactly. It didn't accomplish anything useful whatsoever. It just killed us all.
Eric Rosenbaum: But, but…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right, says Ministers.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Onwards, or more listening to the insane.
Tim Sackton: No, let's keep going, please.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, you step through the next room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it is very clearly an animal lab.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): For experiments on animals.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I feel like you all probably collectively have more experience than me, so, like, let me just, like, go around and
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Among the five of you, what is one thing that's in this animal experimentation lab?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But everyone just… Shout when I build it.
David S. Kong: A million.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
David S. Kong: Lizards.
Eric Rosenbaum: Well, there's walls of cages, but then there's also these wheeled contraptions that are, like, something that you use to take a restrained animal out of the cage, but it's still restrained, so you can wheel it over to a piece of equipment.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's kind of a box with a hole that the head sticks out of, and you clamp it shut over the body.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's horrible and wonderful. Yeah, definitely that.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Mike: It's just a bunch of fur on the ground.
Mike: No clear source.
Mike: Yeah, and.
David S. Kong: Animal skins.
Mike: Not even skins, partial skins maybe? But not like, identifiable.
Eric Rosenbaum: Bowls, little water bowls.
David S. Kong: Scraps, skin scraps.
Eric Rosenbaum: the sort of like veterinary A medical station, like, syringes and gauze and… Scissors and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The far end of the room, you think you can see a corpse lying on the ground. What else?
Tim Sackton: Pay away from the corpse.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
Tim Sackton: I said, stay away from the corpse to everybody.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: Can we get a little closer to see if there's any fungus on it?
Tim Sackton: Can we tell? I mean, we can't be more than 30 feet away because every room is 30 by 30.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can only see its feet sticking around a row of cages.
Mike: Oh, so this is a human corpse. Sorry, I thought you meant an.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, no, no, human corpse. You can see boots.
Kate Sackton: Are there, like, animal skeletons?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, so inside of the cages in this room, the, there are,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Animal skeletons and animals in different stages of decomposition.
Eric Rosenbaum: This.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): shattered glass in one of the cages where it looks like a colony of rats was trying to get out through some kind of like intentional concerted effort.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's another cage at the other far end of the room where the glass is just broken, and it's not clear what was in there before it got out.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are ant farm terraria.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Where the ants have these funny, long tendrils coming out of the top of their heads, as they go about their business, and as you come over to look at them, every one of them stops and turns and looks at you, looking back at them, all exactly at the same time.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, God.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's like butter to sips.
Tim Sackton: Let's… Let's move on quickly.
Kate Sackton: Stay away from the ants, too.
Tim Sackton: Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministry says, okay, the… Exit we need to go through is, It's, just…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Pass the boots. Here we go.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And she,
Mike: Take out my… I mean, I'm gonna…
Mike: I am fully assuming this body is going to wake up and try to.
Tim Sackton: I'm going to take out my shield and I'm also going to summon
Tim Sackton: Flickering flame into my hand with produced flame.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And.
Tim Sackton: Just holding it there.
Kate Sackton: Should we just light it on fire from here and see what happens?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As Ministeus is walking down the corridor in that direction, and you're pondering, he's about halfway to where those boots are when there's another cross walkway.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you see what looks like a hand reach out and pull him down in that direction out of sight.
David S. Kong: Fuck.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We should roll initiative at this point.
David S. Kong: Wow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tim, is there an easy way to do a battle map? We can…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Avoid it, but if there is, it'd be handy.
Tim Sackton: So… Your options are… if…
Tim Sackton: If you haven't set anything up, it's…
Tim Sackton: Not super simple. You can use the Rule 20. Mike was using the Rule 20. I mean, sorry, not the Rule 20, the D&D Beyond.
Kate Sackton: Yo, y.
Tim Sackton: But…
Mike: Probably can't be a host.
Mike: Because you… try… try just clicking on… Try clicking on D&D Beyond.
Mike: If you just click on Play D&D and click on Maps VTT.
Kate Sackton: Mike, it's 10:30 PM. Do you know where your children.
Tim Sackton: Hear you?
Mike: Oh, hi, Isaac. Yes, I know where my child is. They just came home.
Kate Sackton: Just checking.
Kate Sackton: Because I was at a bar with them, it was crazy.
Mike: I know you are in a bar with them.
Kate Sackton: All right, bye. Have fun.
Tim Sackton: I'm wearing shorts.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think so.
Mike: You might have to, like, drop a link into the chat or something.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Here we go.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Apologies for the slowness, I mostly just want to get the,
Tim Sackton: You need to display a scene.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Existence.
Tim Sackton: Oh, here we go.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: True.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I don't know.
Tim Sackton: I don't know.
David S. Kong: by the way guys just Spotify there's like like D&D there's like 10 D&D combat music lists 10 D&D like you know ominous dark you know dungeon it's like and it's pretty good like it's like.
Tim Sackton: I use those a lot.
David S. Kong: They're great.
Eric Rosenbaum: I see Edric on there.
Mike: Yeah, if you just click,
Mike: The little human-looking… the little token-looking thing, but… Are you guys in real plenty?
Tim Sackton: No, we're just using D&D Be.
Mike: Yeah. Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't.
David S. Kong: Oh, okay.
Mike: Eric, if you just click the thing between the compass and the…
Mike: sticky note, the little person icon, and click on Players, you should be able to add yourself.
Mike: Just hit the little plus.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's next year.
Eric Rosenbaum: You're him.
David S. Kong: Wait, where do you add yourself?
Mike: Click on the little token icon.
Eric Rosenbaum: The second to last tool.
Mike: It's the last icon.
David S. Kong: Oh, I see, okay, token browser… And then click.
Mike: I have players and Cato Min is there.
David S. Kong: Okay. Oh, I don't have a thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Can you see the thing I just placed?
Mike: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): When you click on it, like, do you get.
Mike: No.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Is it labeled, or…
Mike: It would reduce threat, yes. But if you click the little edit icon, you can change what it's called.
David S. Kong: Reduced threat to you. Good. Oh, fungus. P.
Mike: And if you want to hide it, you can… you should be able to click on it and say…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: like, hidden or something? There's a way to hide it, I forget what it is
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Or you could do the fog of war.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But again, I can't remember how to do any of this, and I can't do it, because Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Let me just add one.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Mushroom Man, that can't be dangerous at all.
Mike: And now we have to remember.
Eric Rosenbaum: Alright, what can my character do in this situation?
Mike: I was gonna say, I need to remember, like, what Dietrich can do. Like, he's pretty good at this situation.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So we've… We've fought. We've… Been in several combats.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Together.
Tim Sackton: So, I think our usual strategy is… Charo turns into a…
Tim Sackton: creature of some kind. In this case, it's probably gonna be a tiger.
Tim Sackton: Charo and Idrick form the front line.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Tim Sackton: And I can't remember, Eric, do you use… are you Meili or…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Or… Bows.
Eric Rosenbaum: Or what.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Are you like daggers and short swords or are you.
Tim Sackton: Like a crossbow.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I think I'm daggers.
Eric Rosenbaum: I don't know if my actions are set up correctly here. I see unarmed strike, but no dagger attack.
Tim Sackton: Your problem is you have no inventory. You just need to give yourself equipment, and then you'll be fine.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Eric Rosenbaum: I did that already. Okay.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: So I need like a dagger.
Tim Sackton: Yes, you probably want… several daggers, and… A short sword.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Tim Sackton: And then, typically, you would make…
Tim Sackton: You would attack with your shortsword first, and then…
Tim Sackton: With your dagger second, and you can make both attacks in one turn.
Tim Sackton: And if you hit with the short sword, then you have advantage on the attack with the dagger.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, so I added two daggers and a short sword.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Eric Rosenbaum: actions thing.
Eric Rosenbaum: An update.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You have to equip them.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So…
Eric Rosenbaum: There we go.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, now you're good.
Tim Sackton: Okay, what's happening?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right, okay, so…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Looking at this, basically, those are,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The drawn-on spots are rows of
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tables and containers, and you should treat them like total cover, even though you can see through them in some places.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The door is straight ahead of you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: the mushroom man corpse, the feet are sticking out, and then presumably something grabbed Ministhius and pulled him off to the side. How do I see,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Sorry, how do I see initiative?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: if you.
Mike: Here in the world.
Tim Sackton: I don't have the budget.
Mike: There should be a.
Tim Sackton: Sorry about that.
Mike: There should be a start combat.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do I have to do anything to give my monsters initiative?
Mike: If you click Start Combat, You… sorry, it's been a while since I've used this.
Tim Sackton: You need to add them to combat and then you need to roll initiative for them.
Mike: If you…
Mike: So if you… There should be a…
Mike: There should be, like,
Mike: I forgot how you start a combat. This should be an option for starting the combat somewhere.
Eric Rosenbaum: Maybe this is a diplomacy situation.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: If you want to hide a creature, if you click on the creature and click hide, it should disappear first.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Mike: I'll walk.
Tim Sackton: Did they both actually roll, like, zeros for initiative?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You should be able to type in our initiative numbers.
Mike: Like, that's not necessarily the right order.
Tim Sackton: No, it's not the right order.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay, that's the right order.
Tim Sackton: Wait, Edric holds a 14.
Mike: Yeah. Did everybody else roll better than a 14?
Tim Sackton: No, I rolled worse than 14.
Eric Rosenbaum: I got a 20, I rolled a 20, so I got a 25.
David S. Kong: Natural 20.
David S. Kong: 22.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Tim Sackton: And so… Tarek has alert, so you usually don't want to go first, because you want.
Eric Rosenbaum: Correct.
Tim Sackton: Somebody in combat, so you can get sneak attack.
Tim Sackton: Utrecht usually does want to go first.
Mike: Egypt definitely wants to go first.
Tim Sackton: So, Tariq and the injection swap.
Mike: 22.
Mike: Schwartz, does this scale right at 60 feet to the other end?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 30 feet.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So those are.
Mike: So each of these squares is actually…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Each of these squares is actually…
Mike: One half a square.
Eric Rosenbaum: There are.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's correct, yes, it's half.
David S. Kong: So how far away are we.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So. Everything's fine.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Plus.
Kate Sackton: Everything's close.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah.
Mike: So it's 30 feet.
Mike: It's 30 feet to the other end, right? So we're…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We're only 15 feet away from that, right? Like, we're probably a little bit more spread out.
David S. Kong: Oh, nice.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay. Hey, tell me… tell me the initiative order, is this…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Correct, or do I need to change them.
Tim Sackton: May?
Eric Rosenbaum: Thank you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: May? Alright.
David S. Kong: Me too.
Tim Sackton: 14 and make Edric 25.
David S. Kong: And then Cato Min is 2.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Done.
Mike: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That should be the right order. Yeah, go.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So…
Mike: These tables… these are just, like, tables, right?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep, they have stuff on them, so they'd be challenging, like, to jump over, but…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Well, and I just jump over them.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I,
Mike: Sure.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: If that's only 15 feet.
Mike: Right? Can I like, you know, I'm gonna, so first I'm gonna…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: and turn.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Good luck.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Rough.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Train, okay, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right? So first, you know, I'll shout out to the Night Queen, take out my…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: My thing. And what I'd like to do…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: is end up… sorry, where's the map? I would like to end up…
Mike: Standing.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Like, I'd like to go, like, like that, and I'm standing on this table.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Would I be able to reach down?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, sure, man.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: A three foot table, two and a half foot, so yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So I'd like to end up there.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: If it's regular difficult terrain, I should have enough move, one…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right, but if these are only…
Mike: two and a half feet instead of five feet, I have 30 feet, so that's only.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That totally works.
Mike: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I love it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So then I will just… I will just… smash the… Mushroom dude with my… With my, and hammer.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah. All right. What does he look like.
Mike: What does this thing look like?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's Alden. It's… it is a… Wow. He's dressed differently, but otherwise…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Perfectly identical.
Mike: All right, great, awesome.
Mike: Terrible.
Mike: Oh, we're all ter.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Mike: Nope.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That'.
Mike: No, no, I'm going to use Heroic Inspir.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, that's better.
Tim Sackton: Bards give us some bardic, although maybe you should want to save your bardic, because it's a very limited resource these days.
Mike: So, 19.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 19 is a hit.
Mike: All right, so that's…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 6 damage plus I do another 1d6.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Plus one from my rage. I do a lot more damage than that. So that's, nine… Plus…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 10, 11…
Mike: And what is… sorry, I've never played a Barbarian. What the… let's see, R.
Tim Sackton: I agree, plus two.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Should be plus two, right?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Where does it tell me how much damage my range does?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Activate rage by selecting.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Sorry, this is like…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: They've made it stupidly complicated, where it doesn't tell me how much bonus damage it does until I…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Activate Rage.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So that is 2 extra damage, so… so… 7 plus… 5 is 12.
Mike: Plus one more is 13 damage.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Describe…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): how you do that damage.
Mike: I'm literally taking my two-handed maul and swinging down to try and…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Basically.
Mike: Smash its fleshy body.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, and… Smash.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You do. It doesn't lose its grip, though.
Mike: Bye I've also.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: He's gonna knock it over, so I have a special thing if I hit.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: He has to make a DC… 13.
Mike: DC13…
Tim Sackton: Unsafe.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): EC13, con save, coming up.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Otherwise, he is prone.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Or it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I shouldn't assume it has pron
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 13 beats it or fails?
Tim Sackton: 13/16. I think the world's exactly at 13/16.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He rolls exactly 13. Yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep. So, Stagger's back, and maybe even…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): careens back against the row of tables behind him, but doesn't lose his grip on Nemesthis, and you can see.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That his fingers,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's, like, put a hand on Monisthias' chest, but his fingers have…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: elongated and wrapped around, his entire body grappling him, and Menesius is effectively restrained.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright, anything else?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Nine.
Mike: I'm a third level character, I can only do one thing.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We'll see how well I tune this combat for y'all. Okay
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, and then I click next.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yet.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I think it's me, right Yep.
Eric Rosenbaum: Last second.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Cato, you'.
David S. Kong: I mean.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So I can cast a spell.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That does my the most damage.
David S. Kong: Which is Dissonant Whispers.
David S. Kong: I can do it at a first level for 3D6, or at a second level for 4D6, and I think there's a save involved.
Tim Sackton: He was right at first.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Do what? Do what?
Tim Sackton: first.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right, I will cast Dissonant Whispers.
David S. Kong: And sure, it's one creature of my choice. I can see on a failed save, it takes 3d, oh, it has to make a wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it must, it takes 3d6 psychic damage and must immediately use its reaction if available to move as far away from you as it can using the safest route. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage only.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome. It… Very much fails at save.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Hell yeah!
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, it does… I do… aw, man.
David S. Kong: Only 6 damage.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But…
Tim Sackton: It has to run, which means Egypt gets another.
Mike: I got an attack of an opportunity against it.
David S. Kong: Yeah.
Eric Rosenbaum: But it's going to carry Menestheus with it.
David S. Kong: Teamwork makes the dream work.
Mike: That hits.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dang, that is a hit. Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: Nice.
Mike: Crappy damage, though. Eight damage.
Tim Sackton: Galaga Ridge.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No, no, that adds my rage.
Tim Sackton: Oh, okay.
Mike: I don't get the 1d6+1, that's always the problem.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's only…
Mike: But I can make another con save.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Tim Sackton: You can try and knock it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, yeah, yeah. All right, before I move.
Mike: Yep.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No, it makes it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay. And then it is gonna run as far away as it can, and it disappears around the corner. Now, the, the tables that it's behind over here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): are stacked taller with terraria that you can't see around, so it goes out of sight. As it goes, though, it is dragging Monisthias with it.
Eric Rosenbaum: Let's go.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As it runs, so he also is dragged.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: If it is, if it is medium.
Tim Sackton: which I presume it is, it can.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yep.
Tim Sackton: only move half speed while it's dragging.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Tim Sackton: Sure, it's size.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think that actually, we'll put.
Tim Sackton: Maybe that is half speed.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think so. That's 15 feet, I think.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right. Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Keto, well done.
Mike: That's, yeah, that's like 15 feet from me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tarek, you'.
Eric Rosenbaum: Alright, so… Can I, with the move of 30.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh, you can definitely get.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, so I will… Bud.
Tim Sackton: Unfortunately, this now messes up Park's turn.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Mike: Because you can't get Europe. You have.
Tim Sackton: Ally, so you can't get sne.
Mike: Can't get sneak attack.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: Plus there's two of.
Kate Sackton: This this is an ally.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: He's not.
Mike: We don't know if the corpse is going to come alive or not.
Mike: Just be careful there. Don't get exposed by yourself.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh.
Tim Sackton: I feel like it's in character for Tarek to get exposed out by himself.
Kate Sackton: Okay.
Mike: It's also a character for Edric to shout out, be careful there, don't get exposed.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So.
Mike: Whether you pay attention is up to you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Taric just runs up and starts hacking away at the tendrils around Menestheus, so…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Tarek, as you round the corner.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The corpse's eyes open, and it sits up so that it's sitting on the ground, staring directly at you.
Tim Sackton: Oh, well, you have advantage on things that are prone, so attack it, you get sneak attack.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, nice.
Eric Rosenbaum: I didn't know that.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's good to have a DM in the party. Alright.
Eric Rosenbaum: So that means I stop here.
Eric Rosenbaum: And attack the newly awakened mushroom men.
Eric Rosenbaum: And I start with short sword, you said?
Tim Sackton: Start with short sword. Although it doesn't matter in this case.
Tim Sackton: Actually, in this case, you're better off starting with Dagger.
Tim Sackton: Cool.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I started… Because…
Eric Rosenbaum: Too late, I started with a short sword.
Tim Sackton: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I rolled a big seven.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, but I have advantage, or.
Tim Sackton: You have advantage 'cause it's prone.
Eric Rosenbaum: Roll again.
Eric Rosenbaum: Big 6 that time.
Eric Rosenbaum: So I swing and smash my short sword into… A row of glass bottles.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome shards fly everywhere.
Eric Rosenbaum: Umm.
Eric Rosenbaum: And then… quickly…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Switch over to daggers.
Eric Rosenbaum: Rolling a 15, the first one, and again, advantage.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, 15 is a hit.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Tim Sackton: Roll advantage for the crap.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, nice, thank you.
Mike: You should always just see it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No crit.
Eric Rosenbaum: Well, the advantage isn't activated, I don't know why, but anyway.
Eric Rosenbaum: And then the damage… I have this, like… Extra damage feature, what's that?
Mike: 2d6 extra probably sneak attack damage.
Tim Sackton: Sneak attack.
Tim Sackton: So it's… you do 1D4 plus 3 plus 2D6.
Eric Rosenbaum: All right, so the 1D4 plus 3.
Eric Rosenbaum: How can that be 15?
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, it did both, I see.
Tim Sackton: It applied the sneak attack for you, probably.
Eric Rosenbaum: So that's 15.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Wow.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 15 on the on the corpse guy.
Eric Rosenbaum: And now I have one more dagger.
Mike: No, you can't make 3 attack.
Tim Sackton: No, you can only make two attacks.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, okay, okay. So I'm done.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Are you, are you Road?
Tim Sackton: To watch a fight.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Success action.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can use your bonus action.
Tim Sackton: Well, I don't know how much movement you have left.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Also, do you get cutting action disengage?
Mike: At third level?
Mike: Yeah, that'.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, yeah, If you have enough movement, you should do that in retreat.
Eric Rosenbaum: I moved 10 squares, which is like…
Mike: 10 squares would be…
Tim Sackton: Five.
Mike: You should have 12 squares.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: to 30.
Eric Rosenbaum: So I can disengage, I'll just come straight back.
Tim Sackton: Yes.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Nicely done. Thank you Alright.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Have you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right,
Kate Sackton: Nadine moves just to get in view of…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Something?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: As long as she can see around the corner.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then she casts Sacred Flame.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: To burn, I guess, the…
Kate Sackton: One with the…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: One sitting on the ground.
Tim Sackton: Do the more damage button.
Kate Sackton: Okay, for the one that's holding an assist, then.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Read the description for Sacred Fl.
Kate Sackton: Flame-like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a dex saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage.
Kate Sackton: It has no benefit whatsoever.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Is fire its own damage type? So, like, it's saying radiant here, specifically?
Tim Sackton: Radiant is not fire.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
Kate Sackton: It's called Sacred Flame, but it doesn't do flame damage.
Mike: It's a sacred flame. It's radiant.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's holy light, not… Bye.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What's the save? I rolled an 11.
Mike: Should be a third se.
Tim Sackton: Bells.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): How much damage did you say?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Just two.
Kate Sackton: I went with this attack because I thought it was flame, but…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's not.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Kind of flame, so that's the damage I did.
Kate Sackton: And then, as a bonus action, I will cast…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Bardic Inspiration on…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Charo.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Or give her a Bardic Inspiration.
Kate Sackton: At which point, I become invisible.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Awesome.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright, Mushroom Man Corpses up next.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Mushroom Man Corpse stands up, And reaches his hands out towards Tarek.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Both of his hands towards you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
David S. Kong: Reaching out…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right, you're within 10 feet, right?
Tim Sackton: Yeah, yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Plus four. The first roll is a 23.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh shit, so is the second roll.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm an AC13, so, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I rolled two natural 19s in a row.
Tim Sackton: You should add, you should probably have armor though.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, well…
Tim Sackton: Add studded leather to your inventory.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay, okay, okay.
Mike: They'.
Tim Sackton: That'll make your ACs like 16.
Tim Sackton: or 15. Sorry.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You take…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 14 points of damage.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And are grappled.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's cool. 14.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's more than half of my, oh man.
David S. Kong: The third level.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, oh boy.
Tim Sackton: The DM might not have realized that, but it's okay, we're gonna.
David S. Kong: We got this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, no, you totally got this.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At the same time, the other mushroom man who's got Ministhius
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): grappled and held in his two hands. And so, oh, I should have said… So, these hands reach out on these arms that stretch towards you. Oh, the foreshortening is working perfectly. And the fingers, get super long and wrap all the way around your body.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I'm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Holding you in place.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And while he does that, the other mushroom man,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: is holding Menestheus in place, and almost, like.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Frothersome lifts him towards the corpse one that's come up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And on the chest of the corpse one, the one that's just grappled you, you see that 4 or 5 different mouths all open simultaneously in its chest, and it pushes its chest against.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Menestheus, hello!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What a fact.
Mike: So that'.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): screaming and bleeding, screaming uncontrollably, and.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, bleeding uncontrollably.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's not.
Mike: Bad.
Eric Rosenbaum: Also, I don.
David S. Kong: We should stop that. How do we stop.
Eric Rosenbaum: I don't want to be in that situation, ideally.
Kate Sackton: Wait, it's attacking. Is that an attack?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, that was an attack, so it… those were all of its attacks.
Kate Sackton: In light of the attacking that is happening, Avian casts silvery barbs.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: To distract the triggering creature, and… encourage another creature.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What does it do?
Tim Sackton: It has to reroll one of the 19s.
Tim Sackton: Potentially turning a hit into a miss.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, very good.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, actually, that's a 9 with the second hand attack.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So in that case, you get a deck save, so if both hands hit you, you're automatically grappled, if one hand hits you, you get a deck save, so…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Got it.
Eric Rosenbaum: So I get to make a de.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep, and only 7 damage for you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, nice.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, I heal… let me just heal 7.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's nice.
Tim Sackton: That ends your invisibility, though, by the way.
Kate Sackton: I know, I know, but it was cool then.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Definitely.
Eric Rosenbaum: And also…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Total.
Kate Sackton: So I get to direct.
Mike: Somebody else gets advantage on the next one.
Kate Sackton: Advantage on the next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.
Tim Sackton: Give it to me.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, it's you two.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: There you go.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, so… After that…
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm disappointed I'm not grappled.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's…
Tim Sackton: As Charo is running forward, he begins to elongate.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And stretch.
Tim Sackton: And about halfway there, he's now turned fully into a tiger.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: glowing with a little bit of moon energy as he swings forward, with a VIN's blessing, and strikes at the…
Tim Sackton: Corpse that was tackling, That was attempting to grapple
Tim Sackton: Tarek, and that is a 13 to hit, even with advantage.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): 13 just barely will not do it.
Tim Sackton: So what's your bardic die?
Tim Sackton: Is it a D6?
Kate Sackton: How do I look that up? I'm looking, I'm trying to look that up.
Tim Sackton: I assume it's a D6.
Tim Sackton: It's not the end to level eight.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Good.
Tim Sackton: So that changes it to a 16.
Kate Sackton: It was a D6. You were right.
Tim Sackton: Does a 16 hit?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yes, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Tim Sackton: Okay, so glowing with moon energy.
Tim Sackton: Tiger, Tarek, Leaps… How do I… can you pull up your character sheet on…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It.
Mike: If you click on your character.
Mike: You have to change to arrow, and then click on your character, and then click on the little…
Mike: Icon next to your name.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, I got it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Ahhh…
Tim Sackton: So that's 2d6.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, so that's a total of 10 points of slashing damage, and the…
Tim Sackton: Creature is prone.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, right.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Awesome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ahhh…
Mike: That's the corpse, dude.
Tim Sackton: That's the corpse. Y.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Corpses back on the ground again.
Mike: Is that the one who hasn't moved yet or the one who has?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): one that has.
Tim Sackton: And that will end my turn.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He now comes to the other mushroom man who's got Ministhias.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he is going to reach out his second hand towards the tiger.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And roll… 16?
Tim Sackton: That hits. That's my.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, so 7 points of damage, and then, dex save for grapple.
Tim Sackton: This character sheet is not very good. Okay, Dex.
Tim Sackton: Dang.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: is, 21.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, absolutely. You dodge out of the way of the grasping, tendril-like fingers, and it starts to retract back in again.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then this one.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): six or seven different humanoid mouths open in its chest, and it pulls Menestheus against itself and starts rending and, chewing on him, and he is not looking good.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: -Oh.
Mike: So, which,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, bye.
Mike: Right.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Patrick, you Which one has…
Mike: Menesthes, it's both of them are chewing on him.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So he's grappled by the one to his left.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And he was chewed on by the one to his right, but the one to his right has since been knocked prone, so is no longer actively chewing.
Mike: Okay.
Mike: It's a Tricky to get… are you… you're actually large, so you're taking up a lot of space.
Tim Sackton: Yes, I mean, all of our sizes are totally wrong for the scale, but that's fine, we're just gonna ignore that.
Tim Sackton: You can get around me, there's still… Space by the door.
Mike: Yeah, I just don't know if I could get to the one in the.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But…
Tim Sackton: Not the one that's prone, you have advantage.
Mike: I know, I know.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But I think the one on the back's more damaged, but that'.
Mike: I'll come up to the one in the front. I'll charge it. I'll shout.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: at it as I run towards it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then I will… But I have advantage, so… I will…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That's.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, that.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No crit.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, I did crappy damage again.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: plus an additional 1D6+1, so it's that 8.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 13 damage
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right. They are both bloodied by this point.
Mike: Okay,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's all I can do.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, take care.
Mike: I guess he's on the ground. Mercy's doesn't work like…
Mike: Is Meneses, like, dying? How badly hurt is Meneseses.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's still conscious, but… You're not sure why he is still conscious, given the amount of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Dammit, she is sustained.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Kittle, you're up. T
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't hear you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I can't hear you.
David S. Kong: Sorry, I was gonna say, should I continue to use spell slots or should I…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Not do that.
Mike: Do you have any cantrips.
David S. Kong: I do. I can do the vic.
Mike: But I mean, I don't know, Misty's looks like he's about to die.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Then use a spell slot.
Tim Sackton: I think one more level one is fine.
David S. Kong: How do I tell how many level 1 spells I have?
Mike: If you click on spells, it'll show you.
David S. Kong: Use one.
Mike: 3 or 4?
Tim Sackton: Okay.
David S. Kong: Yep.
Tim Sackton: One, you gotta check off one that you already used.
David S. Kong: That's what I'm saying. But I still have three more. All right, cool. I'll do that again. I'll do Distant Wisdom again. Yeah, I'll do Distant Wisdom.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Well.
David S. Kong: Or,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And here comes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That is a 9? This guy's not…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Real wisdom heavy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): having had their brains replaced by mushrooms.
David S. Kong: We love that. So that does…
David S. Kong: 10 damage, and they now need to run far away.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry, tell me again which one was targeted with this?
David S. Kong: Target that. The most advent.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: age is fine.
Mike: Target the pro one.
Tim Sackton: It's hard to get the prone course, but we'll have to crawl away, and both Idrick and I can ha.
David S. Kong: Cool, I do that.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Awesome. Alright, 10 damage you said.
David S. Kong: Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
David S. Kong: This is a cool.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Awesome. Okay. Yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It starts to scramble away, it's almost like it's coming apart, like…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Chunks of its body are, like… falling off.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Tim Sackton: And both of us hit, so maybe it's going to die.
Mike: I have not rolled above a 3 on frickin' damage, but that's okay. 8 damage again.
Tim Sackton: I…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right, with those.
Tim Sackton: It's, 11 for me.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You… Smash it to pieces, and it's like, in that final hit, its body just comes apart, like.
Mike: I'll hold my breath.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sl the other piece, too, is that once it's dead and its bodies come apart.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): it doesn't stay together in a human shape, exactly. It's more like it was a… like a… a jigsaw puzzle of different components that just…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: sort of fragments into mush. Like, you can't even tell that it's a… Person.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: For the most part, except that its head is still…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No, no, no, I did that wrong.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It does not come apart into mush.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Its body is still there, chunks of it are falling off, but it's still there in a body-shaped.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But it's.
Mike: Okay?
Eric Rosenbaum: Huh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, well done, Tarek, you're up.
Eric Rosenbaum: So what's the state of the other one now?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Bloodied, still grappling Ministhius?
Eric Rosenbaum: Alright, so I'm just gonna try again to cut him free with my short sword, so I will…
Eric Rosenbaum: Leap… I can leap over this table.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: Here.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah. Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: So short.
Eric Rosenbaum: Sword, sword, attack…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's a 16 to hit. That's a hit.
Eric Rosenbaum: And so that's…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Do I just…
Eric Rosenbaum: Does it automatically use my sneak attack? It does, so that.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 3.
Tim Sackton: No, you don't have.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Unless… Minestius counts as a…
Mike: Yeah, you don't have advantage. You won't have sne.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It was the best exit count.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He's grappled. He is an ally. I don't know. How do you read in that situation?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Is he, is he…
Tim Sackton: He's not taking turns in combat, so I would say no. He's a non-combatant, he's not a threat to the creature.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think that's fair. All right, regular Dan.
Tim Sackton: But, now you have advantage, so if you hit with your dagger, you get sneak attack on the dagger.
Eric Rosenbaum: Right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sorry, how much damage was that on the short sword?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So it's four without the sneak attack.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Got it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then, attack with a dagger.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's 19 to hit.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's a hit.
Eric Rosenbaum: Now I get the sneak attack damage, so that's 12.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All right.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: This mushroom man, it's not looking good, but it's still… it's doing okay
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And I will, I can do the…
Eric Rosenbaum: Whatever it's called, disengage sneak.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Tim Sackton: Cutting action, disengage.
Tim Sackton: Jump back over the table.
Mike: Did you use your bonus action for your second.
Tim Sackton: No, he has Nick.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Fuck her. All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Hey Dean.
Kate Sackton: All right, well…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Over the table? Around the table? I don't know. It's a tight space. I'm sure I get there.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I get there.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you. Or…
Kate Sackton: I guess, can I just see it from where I was, or is the table — you said these were tall tables, so I better go around to be able to see it.
Kate Sackton: Yeah.
Kate Sackton: But I'm still gonna do a ranged attack. I'm gonna…
Kate Sackton: hit it with guiding bolt, because I want this to be over.
Kate Sackton: I don't know why that… I don't understand that at all.
Kate Sackton: Alright, I'm trying to cast a spell, and nothing is happening, but… Book, book…
Mike: I'll make an attack roll. Guiding Bolt's an attack roll spe.
Kate Sackton: Thank you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Modifiers on that?
Kate Sackton: No, I don't think I have any.
Tim Sackton: What do you mean?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Do you have a Uribear spell attack?
Mike: Bell attack should be plus.
Tim Sackton: But I'.
Kate Sackton: Oh, well thank you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Why me?
Mike: But if you clicked your spell roll, it probably already included the modifier.
Kate Sackton: I didn't click my spell roll, I just rolled the dice, because I didn't know how…
Mike: So add 5.
Kate Sackton: It's the right thing. So yes, so 13.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Just barely misses. All right. Oh, that's painful.
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Kate Sackton: Yep, that'.
Mike: Oh, and now we get to turn. Dam.
Tim Sackton: Wait, was this the one that went first or the one that went second of the two of them?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This was the one that went first. This was the one that grabbed Menestheus the very first moment.
Tim Sackton: No, I mean in the initiative order, because I got deleted from the initiative, but I was in between the two of them.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think this is the one that went first.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I think.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't actually.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Doesn't matter.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, sorry about Zeleny. Okay, so the first thing that it does is it pulls Ministhias in even closer.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): wrapping one arm of his body around, like he's trying to pull Ministhius inside.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): As terrifying as Meneses' screams have been, and he's just been screaming.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Non-stop, since it first started biting and chewing on him.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: What's even worse, and even more ominous, and even more terrifying.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Is that he falls completely silent now.
Mike: Do any of the bards have healing spells.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): See him move.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or breathe.
Kate Sackton: Word.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then, the Mushroom Man will look,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And sort of see itself…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Out.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Classed and outgunned, and instead take it secondhand.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And reach it around Minas Tirith also.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: To do… More damage to his corpse.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And to try and stuff him inside its body.
Tim Sackton: Is he, like, dead dead, or, like, zero hit points and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He has zero hit points and one failed death save now.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, boy.
Tim Sackton: Okay, I'm gonna run over there and I'm gonna cast Cure.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome! How much does that heal?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I'm about to roll.
Tim Sackton: So that's… 10.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Awesome.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): he opens his eyes and takes a deep breath in, Aha.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then, seeing what's happening to him right now, immediately just begins screaming again.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Flailing and thrashing around, trying to get away.
David S. Kong: Chris.
David S. Kong: Progress.
Mike: This, this guy's, it's my turn, right?
Mike: Tim, do you have anything else you.
Tim Sackton: I don't have any useful bonus actions, so it's your turn.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Mike: I'm gonna… I'm going to,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: There we go.
Mike: Look at, like, this creature looks fairly badly hurt at this point.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, yeah, yeah, very.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
Mike: I'm going to just…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You know, Ajax has already been, sort of.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: swinging with this, like, this, like, almost, sort of, zealot fury. And he's just gonna, like, totally let his guard down.
Mike: And just go all in on the attack.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Using reckless attack to give myself advantage.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But also… Happened.
Tim Sackton: I'm also going to move.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Move here.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So that if Tara climbs… I mean, Idrick's probably gonna kill him, but just to make sure…
Tim Sackton: Tarek's got somebody within range.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, cool, cool.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, I'll…
Mike: Like, this corpse isn't even really there anymore.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it is still there. It is still.
Tim Sackton: But you can tell.
Mike: I can step past it, right? So I'll go over to there.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then I will swing at this guy with advantage.
Mike: That's not going to do it.
Mike: Nope, but 15 probably will.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes, it will.
Mike: Okay, so nine damage plus an additional…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Stop it.
Mike: So, 16 total damage.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'd like to call it that, with that mall, you swing, like…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): two-hand, like a… a batter against a baseball, into his head.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And the mall goes through the head and smashes into the wall.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Behind it. Just… cleanly… decapitating… And destroying this thing… Umm…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): With, A fluff of… Seeds.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): They come up into the air.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): From where the head used to be.
Mike: Don't also.
David S. Kong: The 95's on.
Mike: All by Brass.
Mike: Turn away. Like, Egypt will be, like, terrified of the seeds and, like, back away immediately.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Everyone who is immediately adjacent should make a con save.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, sh.
Kate Sackton: Does that include… I'm not immediately adjacent.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No, I think… I think just Tiger and Ys.
Mike: 23.
David S. Kong: X.
Tim Sackton: Sorry, hold on. I just got to check the Bard.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The Druid.
Tim Sackton: I get something…
Tim Sackton: About… Consays? Maybe not.
Tim Sackton: I think it's the wild shape. I think it's the…
Tim Sackton: I need to look at the rules in Wild Shape.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Do you think he is your tattoo sc There.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You retain your…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, so I use whichever's higher between my character and the…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: What happened to my… character okay
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh my god, sorry guys, there's too many clickings.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, so my car has plus 2, the tiger has plus 3, so I get plus 3.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But that's.
Mike: Now.
Tim Sackton: Eight.
Mike: That's bad.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Go,
Kate Sackton: Operation?
Tim Sackton: Now.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ahhh…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You're pretty sure you…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Take a breath in at these things.
David S. Kong: No.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, boy.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, wait a minute.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's probably not true.
David S. Kong: Oh, wait, can I cast insp.
Kate Sackton: Not every action. It has to be on our bonus actions.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Right?
Mike: Do you have.
Tim Sackton: I guess I'll do the- I'm gonna do this just cause…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I can't, I'm gonna use Prophetic Vision.
Tim Sackton: And add one, which doesn't do anything at all.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay.
David S. Kong: Oh, wow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah.
Mike: Sorry, I.
David S. Kong: I can'.
Mike: Can't.
David S. Kong: I can use a luck point.
David S. Kong: That's only for me. Not for me.
Tim Sackton: Only for you.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But…
David S. Kong: But…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alden…
Tim Sackton: It's fine, it'll be fine.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Clutches.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: This just… Bloody and… Wounded torso and tries to, like, wrap his clothes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Back around himself again.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Huh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Sort of fashions crude bandages out of them.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Shit.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Umm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We burn them?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, that's a good idea.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Burn.
David S. Kong: Wait, Alden's saying.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Not often.
Kate Sackton: Honestly.
Tim Sackton: RMS with us.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, good. Yeah, those are the authors.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, let's b
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright, it's relatively easy.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The smoke as it goes up…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Doesn't fill the entire room, so there must be some sort of, you know, error.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): cleaning system, or whatever it is. But, they burn. They burn quick. Like, they go up like dry straw. Almost like flash paper. Just this burst, of flame.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yes.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: "Okay," says Ministis.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Umm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Kate Sackton: I mean, does this still look pretty ragged?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, very much so. He's bloodied still.
Tim Sackton: Where you get more than 20 hit points.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Did.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not many, but…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Slightly.
Tim Sackton: is stronger than we are.
Mike: I have 41 hit points.
Tim Sackton: Other than you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I spent a long time doing math in wizard school and hitting the gym.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right, I could do a healing word.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: If we think the situation merits.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: sort of… I mean, I could…
Tim Sackton: Cast another cure wounds.
Tim Sackton: It's probably better use of spell slots.
Kate Sackton: Okay, if you say so.
Tim Sackton: But is anybody else hurt?
Eric Rosenbaum: I could use a little… Nope.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You guys were lucky you had Menisthias to soak up all the, All the killing.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's right.
Tim Sackton: It's another 12 for Ministhias.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That takes him back almost to full. He's in pretty good shape.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): His little wheeze left, but he's okay.
Kate Sackton: And Tarek's less than half?
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm at 17 out of 24, so I'm…
Tim Sackton: That's fine. You'll be fine. You'll.
Mike: Goodbye.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah. Nope.
Mike: Don't worry so much.
Tim Sackton: I'm not gonna use a spell slot on that.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I'll keep an eye on you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Uhhh…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Anything?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): else you want to do in this space before you head.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So what?
Eric Rosenbaum: What animals were they experimenting on in here?
Eric Rosenbaum: Can you tell what kind of creatures they were?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There were rats. There were ants.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're… looks like there's at least one…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Like, caterpillar… larval stage that becomes something else. Hmm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But they all died as larvae, these big chunky grub things.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You see…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, restraint devices that would fit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): A large monkey, or… Sort of darkly medium halfling?
Eric Rosenbaum: Dad.
Eric Rosenbaum: Let's get out of here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright, the next…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): you come into is a plant greenhouse, but it's all dead. Like, everything is dead. You can see there are…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): all sorts of plants that were being grown, all behind glass and in containment also, but everything is just brown and withered. You do notice there, dandelions, and you see cattails, you see,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, various wildflowers, you see small shrubs.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sort of a cross-section of plants. Milkweed.
Eric Rosenbaum: Where does the light come from? Are there… Lights, or exterior windows?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, there are, essentially like drift globe lamps.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Mmhm.
Eric Rosenbaum: Are there exterior windows anywhere that we've seen?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's the out there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room you come to is.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: A very picked over armory.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There, in one corner, there's a forge.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: An anvil stocked with different tools and equipment, like for doing repairs. You know, there's a breastplate in the middle of being repaired.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's sewing tables for doing, like, leather armor. There's a big boiling tank for boiling leather.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And then also there's, racks with weapons, mmm…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: there's… everything is pretty ordinary. I mean, there's essentially, you know, any sort of common weapons if you're interested in anything, but they're, you know, nothing…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Nothing magical, just a really well-stocked…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Collection of arms and armor.
Eric Rosenbaum: I'm gonna take an extra dagger or two.
David S. Kong: Hey guys, so what the fuck is this place?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Like, this is, like, what do we think this place is? It's like
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Because at one point, it's a prison for the dude in the middle.
David S. Kong: But then, like, what the fuck is going on with all these rooms? Like, this was the… this used to be a stronghold for the Drancorian cult people.
Kate Sackton: Yes.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): "Not a cult," says Menesthes wheezing.
David S. Kong: I'm not I'm not saying that out loud. This is this is.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, June character.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
David S. Kong: Okay. Okay, fine.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, trust.
David S. Kong: with your character.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, it's.
David S. Kong: Odysseus, have you been here before?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not even a secret society. Have you been here before?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I haven't been in here, but, like, this
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We had a half dozen places like this!
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): All over the world.
Mike: Why were you experimenting on animals?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): that…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I don't.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't… that I don't know. The specifics, all these workrooms I don't understand, but the other spaces, like the meeting space and sleeping space.
Mike: Are you gonna turn into a fungus thing?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What?
Mike: Are you gonna turn into a fungus thing.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Wait, why would you say that?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: What?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Am I gonna turn into a fungus?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, okay.
Mike: Yeah, probably, I think you are.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What? You healed me. What?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Stop it then!
Eric Rosenbaum: Where was he getting bites? Like, on his…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like all over his torso.
Eric Rosenbaum: Is there? So I sort of lean over and see how they're looking.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Bites is not quite the right word, like, chunks of him being bitten off is more accurate here.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I mean, though…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): they're healed. He's almost totally healed. Like, what it looks like is…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like, a bad wound that's had a couple of… at least a few weeks?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's not bleeding, it's sort of scabbed over…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's not really clear, like, is that a good color or a bad color?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's…
Eric Rosenbaum: There's there's no, like, filamentous.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Tendrils are… Buzzy.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can make a medicine check.
Eric Rosenbaum: Not my speciality, but I'll do it.
Eric Rosenbaum: plus zero.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yay.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's a natural 20.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: What?
David S. Kong: Really?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yes.
David S. Kong: That's why we roll the dice.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Holy shit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Okay. Okay, fine.
Kate Sackton: "Full inclusive examination," Terex says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So, the wounds on his chest are perfectly fine.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's no filaments, there's nothing there that you notice or see.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But as he's talking and as he's coughing, what you do notice is, like, inside his mouth, or, like, on his lips, there's something…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sort of fuzzy, or growing?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, God. That's white and filamented.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Inside his mouth?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I'm not gonna say anything about it, I'll just quietly take Charo aside and say.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, we got a problem here.
Eric Rosenbaum: Just, if you look real close at inside that guy's mouth, it's not…
Tim Sackton: I don't think there's anything we can do, but…
Tim Sackton: Try and get him help somewhere.
Eric Rosenbaum: Well, maybe give him a handkerchief.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Or, like, has something around his face, even, maybe? I don't know.
Eric Rosenbaum: Poor guy.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Anything else for the art?
Eric Rosenbaum: Should we tell him.
Tim Sackton: I cannot tell him unless there's something we can do about it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yes.
Eric Rosenbaum: Don't let him bite.
Tim Sackton: Yeah. Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: I wonder if he's gonna start to, like, get worried about fire This will be interesting.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Umm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room…
David S. Kong: It's a ministry.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Ministius, that's his.
David S. Kong: So why are you all, like, researching dandelions? And, like… Animals, and…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That's what's.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I wasn't assigned here. I'm a mapmaker. I keep the charts of where…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Where all of the holes in the connections are.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like I said, I never came any further into this place than the…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The entryway.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I met the.
David S. Kong: Participants.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We went right out the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): to the party.
David S. Kong: Or she's telling the.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright, let's keep going.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Umm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The next room is a… Partially constructed orrery.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): This giant, three-dimensional representation of
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): what Mnisthias says are planes of existence, and do not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Really make anything more than a jumble of.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): spheres connected to other interlocking spheres slowly rotating around each other.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I don't think there's anything…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't think you have enough context to make sense of a sort of a three-dimensional map of the…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Universe, which is a great dodge for also not explaining it to you.
Eric Rosenbaum: Dekker definitely builds a much larger one of these late in his retirement days.
Mike: Play Seeker, we're here.
Tim Sackton: Yep.
Tim Sackton: And we never leave this room.
Mike: My insurance would have to explain it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room is,
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And just… Track this for a sec.
Eric Rosenbaum: I like powering through a lot of rooms, that'.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The next room is just offices.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's lots of like little study carrels, and there's a row, you're going down a corridor, so there's some study carrels for like the the little peons, and then there's a whole row of individual offices with people's names on them. The fancy one in the center of the hall is Celestia.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You see one for the gardener that you met also.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Otherwise, they're all locked.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And there's nothing especially interesting in this one.
David S. Kong: Alright, should we go break into Thalestria's office and see what the fuck is going on here
David S. Kong: Tarek, the rogue lawyer.
Eric Rosenbaum: I think we're okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: Funny you should mention.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I'll investigate the lock.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There is no luck.
Eric Rosenbaum: Oh, we might need to edric it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's a knob.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That doesn't turn.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But there's not… there's not, like, a h.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Google RFIDs.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Sleeping.
Eric Rosenbaum: Yeah, he's fobsmith.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We gotta wake up our guy with the big… Blunt instrument.
Eric Rosenbaum: They opened this door, I think.
Mike: I can smash the door. I kind of lost track of where, why we're smashing a door, but Cheryl smashed it.
David S. Kong: It's Celestria's office.
Mike: Sounds like a good thing to smash open.
Eric Rosenbaum: Just hit it right about there.
Mike: I'll hit it right about there.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Make an attack roll.
Mike: Back row or strength check.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Strength check.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Probably the same.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Boss.
Mike: Yeah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Did I get my proficiency?
Mike: Can I use Athletex to try and break this down.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, to put all your weight in just the right… like, you're trying to get a leverage exactly right?
Mike: 17.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 17 is not…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Good enough. A little chip of stone…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Comes off the door, but it won't do it.
David S. Kong: You want to do it again?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You're.
Mike: And that bridging, yeah.
Mike: I could rage, I'll get the advantage.
David S. Kong: But yeah, I can give you also advantage.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, I think unless… unless you have advantage, I'm not gonna let you do it again. Like, something needs to be sort of different in you.
Mike: Yeah, yeah, that.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You bet.
David S. Kong: Wait, I didn't get the.
Tim Sackton: Is the bar exists?
Tim Sackton: Reddit doesn't give advantage, it just lets you add.
David S. Kong: Oh.
Mike: But I could rage.
Mike: Wait, does rage give me advantage? Rage, I might be wrong.
Tim Sackton: And it gives the advantage on strength checks.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh yeah, it does. Yeah.
Mike: I will… I will call upon the gods to help me here.
David S. Kong: Let's fucking go. Let's get into the office and read the fucking Cliff Notes here. What the fuck is.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: That won't do it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Nope, that's worse.
Mike: the gods are not with me.
David S. Kong: Fucking gods.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Maybe the gods know that there is something… there are some things that should not be disturbed.
Mike: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: that…
Mike: Edric's take here. No, he like puts his ha- he feels himself weaker after a rage and failing. He puts his hammer down and he says, we shouldn't go in there. It's not safe. The gods are telling me it's not safe.
Eric Rosenbaum: term.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Ministhia says, wheezing, "I think we just have a couple of more rooms. I think there's like, there's not many.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Here's the next, the next new one that you get to.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): is a map library.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): and there's Large, you know, those long, flat cases that you can pull out with individual maps.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministheus sinks down in a big leather reading chair under a driftglobe light.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And says, oh, oh, oh, this feels so good to be here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I mean, I haven't been to this one, but in the others, you've got the mathematical library, you've got the map cases.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's not circulating, but it's home.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I can't tell you how many years I spent in rooms like this.
David S. Kong: Hey, sorry for just thinking of this right now.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You know the other places that you mentioned, how many are there?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Better like this that you Personally, I don't know, three or four, probably three.
David S. Kong: Do they all have a prisoner in the middle.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: No.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No, no, no, no. Most of them, you walk through a door and then you walk back again and you're in the same place.
David S. Kong: Is this the only one you've been to that has.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In the middle, I mean…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): At least one of the others has, like, a jail cell, a holding cell, but it's…
David S. Kong: Is it part of corporate policy for you to imprison, you know, like for those that are actually trying to, you know.
David S. Kong: Break into other dimensions and stuff like that? Do you… is that… is that part of your organization's… is that part of the society'
David S. Kong: Methods, let's say, to capture and hold.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Sometimes it…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I know of at least one prisoner who was kept.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: More or less indefinitely.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We use them almost like a… Augury, it could tell the…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It could tell the future, and it… It was this little, like, I don't know.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know if it was an octopus in the shape of a plant, or a plant in the shape of a squid, or a something, but it was this little… this little…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): frondy sort of thing. Have you ever seen those deep-sea creatures with, like, the fronds that come? Like an underwater feather?
David S. Kong: Yeah, sure.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's kept in a tank
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it seemed like water, but I don't know actually what it was filled with.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And you could ask it questions, and it would…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It would flash in one particular way if it was no, and in one particular way if it was yes.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We would use it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We would use it for certain kinds of, of…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't know, foretelling or understanding.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: My mentor said, That it wasn't an…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Augury, like, the God's gift that, instead.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It was an animal that was living its entire life simultaneously.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So it didn't have a past or a future.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And we weren't asking it if something was going to happen.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We were asking it if it was seeing the thing happening.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Freaked me out Spooked me.
David S. Kong: Interesting.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Hmm.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It wasn't from here, wherever it was from, it wasn't But it was a captive.
David S. Kong: You were holding it captive.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It was a captive, you were holding it captive.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yes.
David S. Kong: I'm not saying it's bad, I'm just saying, like, you were fearful of it escaping and doing things that would mess with the fabric of…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: the universe.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: I asked this question, and…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): My mentor gave this elaborate answer that basically boils down to, if you have a pet fish, is it your captive?
Eric Rosenbaum: Mmm.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then we moved on.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
Eric Rosenbaum: That's just a crinoid.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Alright.
David S. Kong: Keep.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Onwards.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yah.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The next room is, oh, wait.
Eric Rosenbaum: Sorry.
Kate Sackton: I'm just curious if there's You can enter.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh, just like, what?
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Places are mapped.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Like, what are the maps dep
Audio shared by David S. Kong: So, opening a drawer at random…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There are cases that are full of maps of different parts of Talgar, some of which you recognize.
Eric Rosenbaum: Okay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Though, of course, things are mislabeled.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And then there are other things which look much more like, almost like blueprints or architectural diagrams. Like,
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): or, like, wiring diagrams. If you've ever looked at, like, a really complex wiring diagram, you know that it corresponds to a real thing, and it shows how the pieces of that real thing fit together.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But you know that it's, like, topologically correct, but the way that it's shown in the diagram itself may not actually correspond to the physical distances between things.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So it's it's hard to make sense of those kinds of diagrams.
Eric Rosenbaum: So it's the topology of something.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Eric Rosenbaum: All right, scratch my head to move on.
Kate Sackton: Are there maps of this part of the Feywild?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Not that you come across. In fact, you don't find a drawer that corresponds to, like, Feywild maps.
Kate Sackton: Worth trying.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The mystic says.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): If I died here and now in a room like this, I would be happy.
David S. Kong: You can stay.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): In order for the door to open, we all have to go together.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: What?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): You can't split the party. The door to the next room will only open if all of the people together walk through it at once.
David S. Kong: See.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All right.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next room is a sort of a tinkerer's lab.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or like a fabrication lab, where there are… But.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Rows of workstations for building or constructing different kinds of things.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I don't think any of you have the proficiencies to sort of make sense of it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): But, like, an artificer's lab.
David S. Kong: Service.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, absolutely, for testing and measuring different kinds of things. There's one of those big barometric pressure things with the different density weights and liquids.
David S. Kong: Kato takes a look around at some of that stuff. This facility is like a giant… I mean, there's like hundreds of people would have been…
David S. Kong: when this was… Operating. It's like…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, the bedroom suggests…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That they had capacity for dozens. And the dining room, too, for dozens at a sitting.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Okay.
David S. Kong: Cool.
David S. Kong: You're gone.
David S. Kong: We saw the Fab Lab, it's kind of like a M.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I think there's only Two more rooms.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ministry says.
David S. Kong: Until they get to room 28.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Mmhm.
David S. Kong: Oh, shit.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): He opens the door.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): So this would be room 25.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And it's another one of these massive, massive mechanical rooms with a listening window on the far end.
David S. Kong: No. Can I hear any more voices?
Kate Sackton: Well, you don't have to go near the notebook. The rest of us can go read the notebook.
Kate Sackton: Kitty goes over there.
David S. Kong: Yeah, it's kind of cool.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): though, you start…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): I'm gonna put things into chat that are written down in the notebook, but you start to hear permutations of this.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Like at a, just a constant low level, like someone or something perseverating around a few ideas and looping over and over in different forms. It's not like it's exactly the verbatim text over and over, but you hear this as soon as you step into the room.
David S. Kong: Nice.
David S. Kong: This playlist is totally hidden right now, too.
David S. Kong: You are leaving through the door in my room. I am always hungry, but now I am so full. Oh, this was from before.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Oh.
David S. Kong: You are killing Dragon, but you are not brave. You are calling yourself Lord, but you are not a Lord. You are sad all the time.
Tim Sackton: Yeah, this is all about a cold day.
David S. Kong: But, sorry, who's, but who's, who's saying what to
David S. Kong: You are bringing five friends to help me. They are outside my room right now. They are hearing me. Oh, fuck. That's us. Shit. They are coming to my door. Fuck.
David S. Kong: Wait, so this is the prisoner talking to who.
Kate Sackton: Older.
Tim Sackton: Hold on.
David S. Kong: You are killing Dragon, but you are not brave. Why are they kill.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: All the…
Tim Sackton: Oh, that killed the dragon.
David S. Kong: Oh, right.
David S. Kong: Fuck, who's the prisoner? Is the prisoner or No.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: This is so cool.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But it's.
Mike: Wait, did we make it to the pr.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: We're one door away.
Mike: Okay, time to wake up.
David S. Kong: This is it for the end part, Mike.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The next door is the timing.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: 26th room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And I think.
David S. Kong: Alright, let'.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): We're going to leave it there.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Alright.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The 26th room.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): is a library. A massive library.
Eric Rosenbaum: Library.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The stacks go…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Floor to ceiling, and they're… Book.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's at least at a ground level, there's.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Desks, reading desks, and tables.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): There's some books which are chained onto the, the shelves that they're on.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: And.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: But.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Inside the door, Against, one side of the room.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: You see…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): What looks like a mechanical torso?
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): with a head on top that's been made out of painted porcelain, made to look like a person, so that there's a number of different plates. There's a forehead plate, and there's little eyes inset that can move and track, and a nose.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And a mouth and cheek plates that go over it, and then a jaw that can raise up and down, on top of an articulated neck that can swivel back and forth.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): The bottom of it is anchored into the desk. It looks, you recognize in it, the sorts of components that you saw in that fabrication, that artificer's lab.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Wow.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And its eyes are closed, and it's looking down, and as you step into the room, Its head…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Lifts up.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And stares directly at you.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And cocks to the side quizzically.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): And that's where we'll leave it for this session.
David S. Kong: All right.
Eric Rosenbaum: Is there anything further about it's like a human looking person, like male, female, like? Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Human sized to.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: The face and head, recognizable in any way here.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Ambiguously gendered, no hair.
Eric Rosenbaum: It's really like an android, a ceramic android.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Or like a Mechanical Turk, like a clockwork.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Clockwork creature.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): That reminds you…
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Maybe you've seen in the city, like a mechanical fortune teller once? Right. Where you put in your coin and it moves around.
Eric Rosenbaum: Spits out the tickets.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah Okay, thank you Okay.
David S. Kong: Oh.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Thank you.
David S. Kong: The tech mag It hasn't.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yeah, sure.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Yep.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Thanks.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: It's just magic ish.
Kate Sackton: I gotta say, with this, like, creepy room background, if Eric slouches just right, and it's just, like, an arm, you just sort of see…
David S. Kong: Dude, totally. Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're lying on that corpse. It's.
Kate Sackton: Yeah, at one point I was like, why is that creature holding a human arm? And I was like, oh wait, part of that's background and part of it's not.
Eric Rosenbaum: Actually, there's no…
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Reason to tell.
Eric Rosenbaum: out a little bit because I leaned on this.
David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah, cuddle with the cuddle. I want to take a screenshot. Wait, Eric, can we lean a little bit more.
Audio shared by David S. Kong: Wait, hold on.
David S. Kong: My screen is slow. Oh, yeah, yeah, there it is. There it is. That's good. Yeah, yeah, just a little bit. And then, and then.
David S. Kong: Yeah, yeah. Oh, that's it, yeah. Okay, yeah, that's great, that's great, that's good. I got it, I got it, I got it.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): No reason to tell him he's inf.
David S. Kong: Schwartz, this is great.
Eric Rosenbaum: Have fun.
David S. Kong: Nice to have a combat this time.
Eric Rosenbaum: I love the variety of settings also.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): Yeah, that worked pretty well.
Eric Rosenbaum: Differe.
David S. Kong: No, that was sick. That was super cool.
Rev. David Schwartz (he/him): It's I, I appreciated the debrief at the end of last session. It was helpful.